[
    {
        "id": "1",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "Your company intends to subscribe to an Azure support plan. \nThe support plan must allow for new support requests to be opened. \nWhich of the following are support plans that will allow this?\nA. Basic\nB. Developer\nC. Standard\nD. Professional Direct\nE. Premier",
        "answer": "BCD",
        "explanation": "All Azure support plans except for the Basic and the Premier plan allow for the opening of new support requests. The Basic plan offers only limited support for billing and subscription management issues and does not include technical support for services. Premier support plans are being phased out and are no longer available for new customers",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "2",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company has datacenters in Los Angeles and New York. The company has a Microsoft Azure subscription.\nYou are configuring the two datacenters as geo-clustered sites for site resiliency.\nYou need to recommend an Azure storage redundancy option.\nYou have the following data storage requirements:\n- Data must be stored on multiple nodes.\n- Data must be stored on nodes in separate geographic locations.\n- Data can be read from the secondary location as well as from the primary location\nWhich of the following Azure stored redundancy options should you recommend?\nA. Geo-redundant storage\nB. Read-only geo-redundant storage\nC. Zone-redundant storage\nD. Locally redundant storage",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Geo-redundant storage (with GRS or GZRS) replicates your data to another physical location in the secondary region to protect against regional outages.However, that data is available to be read only if the customer or Microsoft initiates a failover from the primary to secondary region. When you enable read access to the secondary region, your data is available to be read at all times, including in a situation where the primary region becomes unavailable. For read access to the secondary region, enable read-access geo-redundant storage (RA-GRS) or read-access geo-zone-redundant storage (RA-GZRS).",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "3",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's Azure subscription includes a Basic support plan. \nThey would like to request an assessment of an Azure environment's design from Microsoft. \nThis is, however, not supported by the existing plan. \nYou want to make sure that the company subscribes to a support plan that allows this functionality, while keeping expenses to a minimum. \nSolution: You recommend that the company subscribes to the Professional Direct support plan. Does the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "The solution does not meet the goal of keeping expenses to a minimum. The Professional Direct support plan is a higher-tier support plan that incurs additional costs compared to the Basic support plan. While the Professional Direct support plan does provide access to design assessments from Microsoft, it may not be the most cost-effective option for the company. It would be more appropriate to recommend a support plan that includes design assessments but still keeps expenses low, such as the Developer or Standard support plans.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "4",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are tasked with deploying Azure virtual machines for your company.\nYou need to make use of the appropriate cloud deployment solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Software as a Service (SaaS).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "The solution does not meet the goal. Software as a Service (SaaS) is a cloud computing model where software applications are delivered over the internet. It typically refers to using web-based applications provided by a third-party vendor. However, in this scenario, the goal is to deploy Azure virtual machines, which is an Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) offering. With IaaS, you can deploy and manage virtual machines in the cloud, giving you more control over the infrastructure layer. Therefore, the appropriate cloud deployment solution in this case would be Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), not Software as a Service (SaaS).",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "5",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are tasked with deploying Azure virtual machines for your company.\nYou need to make use of the appropriate cloud deployment solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Platform as a Service (PaaS).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Platform as a service refers to cloud computing services that supply an on-demand environment for developing, testing, delivering, and managing software applications. PaaS is designed to make it easier for developers to quickly create web or mobile apps, without worrying about setting up or managing the underlying infrastructure of servers, storage, network, and databases needed for development. However, in this scenario, the goal is to deploy Azure virtual machines, which is an Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) offering. With IaaS, you can deploy and manage virtual machines in the cloud, giving you more control over the infrastructure layer. ",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "6",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are tasked with deploying Azure virtual machines for your company.\nYou need to make use of the appropriate cloud deployment solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "With IaaS, you can deploy and manage virtual machines in the cloud, giving you more control over the infrastructure layer. ",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "7",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your developers have created 10 web applications that must be host on Azure.\nYou need to determine which Azure web tier plan to host the web apps. The web tier plan must meet the following requirements:\n- The web apps will use custom domains.\n- The web apps each require 10 GB of storage.\n- The web apps must each run in dedicated compute instances.\n- Load balancing between instances must be included.\n- Costs must be minimized.\nWhich web tier plan should you use?\nA. Standard\nB. Basic\nC. Free\nD. Shared",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Standard tier support Custom Domains, Disk Space of 50GB wich is more than enough for the requested plan, and as long as they want to run each web app in a dedicated instance, that means we need 10 dedicated instances for the 10 web apps with a load-balancing service between them, the basic plan only support up to 3 dedicated instances. Finally the Standard plan has the lowest cost compared to Premuim and Isolated pricing tiers.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "8",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are planning to migrate a company to Azure. Each of the company's numerous divisions will have an administrator in place to manage the Azure resources used by their respective division.\nYou want to make sure that the Azure deployment you employ allows for Azure to be segmented for the divisions, while keeping administrative effort to a minimum.\nSolution: You plan to make use of several Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) directories.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure Active Directory (AAD) is Microsoft's cloud-based identity and access management service, helping organizations manage and secure access to applications and resources. Using multiple Azure Active Directory (AAD) instances increases complexity due to separate management, inconsistent security policies, difficulty in collaboration, and challenges in implementing single sign-on across directories.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "9",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your developers have created a portal web app for users in the Miami branch office. The web app will be publicly accessible and used by the Miami users to retrieve customer and product information. The web app is currently running in an on-premises test environment.\nYou plan to host the web app on Azure.\nYou need to determine which Azure web tier plan to host the web app. The web tier plan must meet the following requirements:\n- The website will use the miami.weyland.com URL.\n- The website will be deployed to two instances.\n- SSL support must be included.\n- The website requires 12 GB of storage.\n- Costs must be minimized.\nWhich web tier plan should you use?\nA. Standard\nB. Basic\nC. Free\nD. Shared",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Free = 1 GB\nShared = 1 GB \nBasic = 10 GB \nStandard = 50 GB",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company is planning to migrate all their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription. The virtual machines are currently hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou are required make sure that the intended Azure solution uses the correct expenditure model.\nSolution: You should recommend the use of the elastic expenditure model.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "The solution does not meet the goal. There is no specific expenditure model called the \"elastic expenditure model\" in Azure. When migrating virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription, the appropriate expenditure model to consider is the \"pay-as-you-go\" or \"consumption-based\" model. This means that you will be billed based on the actual usage of Azure resources, such as virtual machines, storage, and networking, on an hourly or per-minute basis. Therefore, the correct solution would be to recommend the use of the \"pay-as-you-go\" expenditure model, not the \"elastic expenditure model.\"",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "11",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company is planning to migrate all their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription. The virtual machines are currently hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou are required make sure that the intended Azure solution uses the correct expenditure model.\nSolution: You should recommend the use of the scalable expenditure model.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "There is no such thing as a \"scalable expenditure model\" in Azure. The two expenditure models in Azure are pay-as-you-go and reserved instances. Pay-as-you-go is the default and most common expenditure model in Azure. It means you pay for resources you consume on an hourly or per-minute basis. It offers flexibility to scale resources up and down as needed. Reserved instances is an expenditure model where you commit to a one- or three-year term for a particular virtual machine instance type, size, and region. This commitment provides you with a discount compared to pay-as-you-go pricing. Since the question states that the company is planning to migrate all of their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription, the correct expenditure model is pay-as-you-go. ",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "12",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company is planning to migrate all their virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription. The virtual machines are currently hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou are required make sure that the intended Azure solution uses the correct expenditure model.\nSolution: You should recommend the use of the operational expenditure model.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Operating expenditures are ongoing costs of doing business. Consuming cloud services in a pay-as-you-go model could qualify as an operating expenditure. ",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "13",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are required to deploy an Artificial Intelligence (AI) solution in Azure.\nYou want to make sure that you are able to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics for the solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Azure Cosmos DB.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure Cosmos DB is a globally distributed, multi-model database service optimized for managing schema-less data at a global scale, offering high availability and low latency. For deploying an AI solution that involves building, testing, and deploying predictive analytics, services like Azure Machine Learning or Azure Cognitive Services are more appropriate, as they are specifically designed for AI workloads, including predictive analytics.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "14",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's Active Directory forest includes thousands of user accounts.\nYou have been informed that all network resources will be migrated to Azure. Thereafter, the on-premises data center will be retired.\nYou are required to employ a strategy that reduces the effect on users, once the planned migration has been completed.\nSolution: You plan to sync all the Active Directory user accounts to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Syncing all the Active Directory user accounts to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) is a common strategy to ensure a smooth migration to the cloud while minimizing the impact on users. This approach is often referred to as implementing a hybrid identity model. By syncing the user accounts to Azure AD using tools like Azure AD Connect, users can continue using their existing credentials to access cloud resources after the migration. This provides a seamless experience for users and reduces the disruption typically associated with migrations. Therefore, the solution of syncing Active Directory user accounts to Azure AD meets the goal of reducing the impact on users during the migration to Azure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "15",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are required to deploy an Artificial Intelligence (AI) solution in Azure.\nYou want to make sure that you are able to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics for the solution.\nSolution: You should make use of Azure Machine Learning Studio.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Machine Learning Studio (classic) is a drag-and-drop tool you can use to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions. ",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "16",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's infrastructure includes a number of business units that each need a large number of various Azure resources for everyday operation.\nThe resources required by each business unit are identical.\nYou are required to sanction a strategy to create Azure resources automatically.\nSolution: You recommend that the Azure API Management service be included in the strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure API Management is a service that helps create consistent and modern API gateways for existing back-end services. It does not provide a direct means to automate the creation of Azure resources. For automating resource creation, services like Azure Resource Manager templates, Azure Automation, or Azure DevOps would be more appropriate as they are designed to handle deployment and automation of resources on Azure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "17",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's infrastructure includes a number of business units that each need a large number of various Azure resources for everyday operation.\nThe resources required by each business unit are identical.\nYou are required to sanction a strategy to create Azure resources automatically.\nSolution: You recommend that management groups be included in the strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Management groups are used to organize resources and manage access, policy, and compliance across multiple subscriptions, but they are not specifically designed for automatically creating Azure resources. Instead, consider using Azure Resource Manager templates (ARM templates) or Azure Blueprints for automating the creation and management of Azure resources.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "18",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's infrastructure includes a number of business units that each need a large number of various Azure resources for everyday operation.\nThe resources required by each business unit are identical.\nYou are required to sanction a strategy to create Azure resources automatically.\nSolution: You recommend that the Azure Resource Manager templates be included in the strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Using Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates is a highly effective strategy for automatically creating and managing Azure resources, especially when you have identical requirements for multiple business units. ARM templates allow you to define your infrastructure as code, specifying the resources, configurations, and relationships in a declarative manner. By creating ARM templates that represent the required resources, you can deploy them consistently across different business units while ensuring that the configurations are identical. This approach is efficient, repeatable, and scalable, making it a suitable solution for automating resource deployment.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "19",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are tasked with deploying a critical LOB application, which will be installed on a virtual machine, to Azure.\nYou are informed that the application deployment strategy should allow for a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. You need to make sure that the strategy requires as little virtual machines and availability zones as possible.\nSolution: You include two virtual machines and one availability zone in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure's SLA for Virtual Machines with a single instance is 99.5% availability. To achieve a guaranteed availability of 99.99%, you would need to deploy the application in an architecture that takes advantage of Azure's higher availability options, such as Availability Zones. For an SLA of 99.99%, deploying the application in at least two Availability Zones would be recommended. This would ensure that your application is highly available across separate physical locations, each with its own power, cooling, and networking, reducing the risk of a single point of failure. Simply deploying two virtual machines in a single Availability Zone would not achieve the desired level of availability.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "20",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are tasked with deploying a critical LOB application, which will be installed on a virtual machine, to Azure.\nYou are informed that the application deployment strategy should allow for a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. You need to make sure that the strategy requires as little virtual machines and availability zones as possible.\nSolution: You include one virtual machine and two availability zones in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Deploying one virtual machine and two availability zones does not meet the goal of achieving a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. To achieve such a high level of availability, you typically need to distribute your application across multiple instances in multiple availability zones or sets.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "21",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are tasked with deploying a critical LOB application, which will be installed on a virtual machine, to Azure.\nYou are informed that the application deployment strategy should allow for a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. You need to make sure that the strategy requires as little virtual machines and availability zones as possible.\nSolution: You include two virtual machines and two availability zones in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Deploying one virtual machine and two availability zones does not meet the goal of achieving a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent. To achieve such a high level of availability, you typically need to distribute your application across multiple instances in multiple availability zones or sets.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "22",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's developers intend to deploy a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. They will also be removing these virtual machines during the same week it was deployed. Sixty percent of the virtual machines have Windows Server 2016 installed, while the other forty percent has Ubuntu Linux installed.\nYou are required to make sure that the administrative effort, needed for this process, is reduced by employing a suitable Azure service.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Microsoft Managed Desktop.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Microsoft Managed Desktop is not an appropriate solution for deploying and managing a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. Microsoft Managed Desktop is a service that provides managed Windows 10 devices for organizations, and it's not designed for managing virtual machines, especially with the frequency and diversity described in your scenario. For managing virtual machines in Azure, a more suitable solution would be to use Azure Automation or Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates. These tools allow you to automate the deployment and management of virtual machines, including the creation, configuration, and deletion of resources. You can define your desired state in code, and these tools will handle the provisioning and management tasks, reducing administrative effort.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "23",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's developers intend to deploy a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. They will also be removing these virtual machines during the same week it was deployed. Sixty percent of the virtual machines have Windows Server 2016 installed, while the other forty percent has Ubuntu Linux installed.\nYou are required to make sure that the administrative effort, needed for this process, is reduced by employing a suitable Azure service.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure Reserved Virtual Machines (VM) Instances.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure Reserved Virtual Machine (VM) Instances are not the most suitable solution for deploying and managing a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis that are also removed during the same week. Reserved VM Instances are used to save costs by committing to a specific VM instance type for a one- or three-year term, which is not aligned with the short-term and frequent deployment and removal pattern described in your scenario. To reduce administrative effort for your specific use case, you might consider using Azure DevTest Labs. Azure DevTest Labs allows you to quickly create environments in Azure while managing costs by setting up policies for resource usage. You can create a lab that aligns with your requirements, including Windows Server and Ubuntu Linux VMs, and allow your developers to deploy and remove VMs easily in a controlled environment.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "24",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's developers intend to deploy a large number of custom virtual machines on a weekly basis. They will also be removing these virtual machines during the same week it was deployed. Sixty percent of the virtual machines have Windows Server 2016 installed, while the other forty percent has Ubuntu Linux installed.\nYou are required to make sure that the administrative effort, needed for this process, is reduced by employing a suitable Azure service.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure DevTest Labs.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure DevTest Labs is a suitable Azure service for managing the deployment and lifecycle of custom virtual machines, especially when they need to be created and removed frequently, as in your scenario. With Azure DevTest Labs, you can create a lab environment where developers can quickly create and manage virtual machines for development and testing purposes. The lab management capabilities allow you to set up policies, quotas, and schedules, which can help reduce administrative effort and manage costs. By using Azure DevTest Labs, developers can easily deploy custom virtual machines with Windows Server 2016 and Ubuntu Linux as needed, and these VMs can be automatically cleaned up or removed at the end of the week. This approach streamlines the deployment and management process, ensuring that administrative effort is reduced while meeting the dynamic requirements of your developers. ",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "25",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "Your company has virtual machines (VMs) hosted in Microsoft Azure. The VMs are located in a single Azure virtual network named VNet1.\nThe company has users that work remotely. The remote workers require access to the VMs on VNet1.\nYou need to provide access for the remote workers.\nWhat should you do?\nA. Configure a Site-to-Site (S2S) VPN.\nB. Configure a VNet-toVNet VPN.\nC. Configure a Point-to-Site (P2S) VPN.\nD. Configure DirectAccess on a Windows Server 2012 server VM.\nE. Configure a Multi-Site VPN",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "To provide remote workers with access to the virtual machines (VMs) in the Azure virtual network (VNet), you should configure a Point-to-Site (P2S) VPN. P2S VPN allows individual remote clients to securely connect to the Azure VNet over the internet using a VPN client installed on their computer. This enables the remote workers to access the resources within VNet as if they were connected directly to the virtual network.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "26",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You have been informed by your superiors of the company's intentions to automate server deployment to Azure. There is, however, some concern that administrative credentials could be uncovered during this process.\nYou are required to make sure that during the deployment, the administrative credentials are encrypted using a suitable Azure solution.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure Information Protection.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure Information Protection is primarily used for classifying, labeling, and protecting documents and emails containing sensitive information. It's not designed for encrypting administrative credentials during server deployment processes. For encrypting administrative credentials during server deployment to Azure, a more suitable solution would be to use Azure Key Vault. Azure Key Vault is a cloud service that allows you to safeguard cryptographic keys, certificates, and secrets used by cloud applications and services. You can store the administrative credentials securely in Azure Key Vault and retrieve them when needed during the deployment process. This ensures that the credentials are properly protected and managed.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "27",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You have been informed by your superiors of the company's intentions to automate server deployment to Azure. There is, however, some concern that administrative credentials could be uncovered during this process.\nYou are required to make sure that during the deployment, the administrative credentials are encrypted using a suitable Azure solution.\nSolution: You recommend the use of Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "No, the recommended solution of Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) does not encrypt administrative credentials during server deployment to Azure. MFA is a solution that adds an additional layer of authentication to the login process, and it can help prevent unauthorized access to resources. To encrypt administrative credentials during server deployment to Azure, a better solution would be to use Azure Key Vault. Azure Key Vault is a cloud-based service that provides secure storage of keys, secrets, and certificates. By storing the administrative credentials in Azure Key Vault, they can be encrypted and protected from unauthorized access.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "28",
        "choices": "ABCDEF",
        "question": "The company would like to develop a cloud solution by making use of Azure Government. \nAzure Government can only be used by certain types of clients to develop cloud solutions.\nWhich of the following are the types of customers that can make use of Azure Government in this situation? \nA. A government contractor from any country\nB. A government entity from any country\nC. A European government contractor\nD. A European government entity\nE. A US government contractor\nF. A US government entity",
        "answer": "EF",
        "explanation": "Azure Government is the mission-critical cloud, delivering breakthrough innovation to US government customers and their partners. Only US federal, state, local, and tribal governments and their partners have access to this dedicated instance.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "29",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company has an Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) environment. Users occasionally connect to Azure AD via the Internet.\nYou have been tasked with making sure that users who connect to Azure AD via the internet from an unidentified IP address, are automatically encouraged to change passwords.\nSolution: You configure the use of Azure AD Identity Protection.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure AD Identity Protection is a comprehensive solution that helps you protect your organization's identities and detect and respond to potential identity-related risks. One of its features is the ability to configure risk-based policies. In this case, you can set up a risk-based policy that triggers a password change prompt for users when they connect to Azure AD via the internet from an unidentified IP address. This helps enhance security by encouraging users to change their passwords in case of suspicious activity.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "30",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company has an Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) environment. Users occasionally connect to Azure AD via the Internet.\nYou have been tasked with making sure that users who connect to Azure AD via the internet from an unidentified IP address, are automatically encouraged to change passwords.\nSolution: You configure the use of Azure AD Privileged Identity Management.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure AD Privileged Identity Management (PIM) manages, controls, and monitors access within Azure AD, Azure, and other Microsoft Online Services. It's used for managing privileged accounts and doesn't directly handle password policies or enforce password changes based on IP address recognition. Instead, to meet the goal, you should consider using Azure AD Identity Protection, which can enforce risk-based conditional access policies that might prompt users for password changes if an unfamiliar sign-in is detected.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "31",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are planning a strategy to deploy numerous web servers and database servers to Azure.\nThis strategy should allow for connection types between the web servers and database servers to be controlled.\nSolution: You include network security groups (NSGs) in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "You can use an Azure network security group to filter network traffic between Azure resources in an Azure virtual network. A network security group contains security rules that allow or deny inbound network traffic to, or outbound network traffic from, several types of Azure resources. For each rule, you can specify source and destination, port, and protocol",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "32",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You are planning a strategy to deploy numerous web servers and database servers to Azure.\nThis strategy should allow for connection types between the web servers and database servers to be controlled.\nSolution: You include a local network gateway in your strategy.\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "A local network gateway in Azure is typically used when you want to establish a connection between your Azure virtual network and an on-premises network or another network outside of Azure. It's not directly related to controlling connection types between web servers and database servers within the same Azure virtual network. To control the connection types between web servers and database servers in Azure, you would typically use Network Security Groups (NSGs), which allow you to define inbound and outbound traffic rules to control the flow of traffic between resources in a virtual network. You might also consider using Azure Firewall or Azure Application Gateway depending on your specific requirements.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "33",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company's Active Directory forest includes thousands of user accounts.\nYou have been informed that all network resources will be migrated to Azure. Thereafter, the on-premises data center will be retired.\nYou are required to employ a strategy that reduces the effect on users, once the planned migration has been completed.\nSolution: You plan to require Azure Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA).\nDoes the solution meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Multi-factor authentication doesn't reduce the effect or have any kind of effect on this issue. MFA is used to verify the reinforce the security to identify a user, but it doesn't help at all in arranging the user's accounts",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "34",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure provides full control of the operating systems that host applications. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure provides the ability to scale the platform automatically. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure provides professional development services to continuously add features to custom applications. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "A PaaS solution does not provide access to the operating system. \nThe Azure Web Apps service provides an environment for you to host your web applications.\nBehind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS.\n However, you have no direct access to the virtual machine, the operating system or IIS.\n\nA PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure does provide the ability to scale the platform automatically. This is known as autoscaling. \nBehind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS. \nAutoscaling means adding more load balanced virtual machines to host the web apps.\n\nPaaS provides a framework that developers can build upon to develop or customize cloud-based applications. \nPaaS development tools can cut the time it takes to code new apps with pre-coded application components built into the platform, such as workflow, directory services, security features, search and so on.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "35",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure provides flexibility between capital expenditure (CapEx) and operational expenditure (OpEx). (Y/N)\n- If you create two Azure VM that use the B2S size, each VM will always generate the same monthly costs. (Y/N)\n- When an Azure VM is stopped, you continue to pay storage costs associated to the VM. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "YNY",
        "explanation": "Storage cost are separate. In Azure stopping VM and de-allocating / deleting VM is different. If you stop VM still you need storage space to store VM image and which will cost you. Cost is Azure have different meters so VM costly will be possibly different at end of month.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "36",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "When you are implementing a SaaS solution, you are responsible for :\nA. configuring high availability\nB. defining scalability rules\nC. installing the SaaS solution\nD. configuring the SaaS solution",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "When implementing a SaaS solution, the provider of the SaaS solution is responsible for configuring high availability and defining scalability rules. The customer is responsible for configuring and using the SaaS solution, but not for installing it.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "37",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You have an on-premises network that contains several servers.\nYou plan to migrate all the servers to Azure.\nYou need to recommend a solution to ensure that some of the servers are available if a single Azure data center goes offline for an extended period.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. fault tolerance\nB. elasticity\nC. scalability\nD. low latency",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Fault tolerance is the ability of a system to continue to function in the event of a failure of some of its components.\nIn this question, you could have servers that are replicated across datacenters.\nAvailability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region. Each zone is made up of one or more datacenters equipped with independent power, cooling, and networking. To ensure resiliency, there are a minimum of three separate zones in all enabled regions. The physical separation of Availability Zones within a region protects applications and data from datacenter failures.\nWith Availability Zones, Azure offers industry best 99.99% VM uptime SLA. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your applications and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.\nReferences:",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "38",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "An organisation that hosts its infrastructure [...] no longer requires a data center.\nA. in a private cloud\nB. in a hybrid cloud\nC. in the public cloud\nD. on a Hyper-V host",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "A private cloud is hosted in your datacenter. Therefore, you cannot close your datacenter if you are using a private cloud.\nA public cloud is hosted externally, for example, in Microsoft Azure. An organization that hosts its infrastructure in a public cloud can close its data center.\nPublic cloud is the most common deployment model. In this case, you have no local hardware to manage or \"keep up-to-date\" everything runs on your cloud provider's hardware.\nMicrosoft Azure is an example of a public cloud provider.\nIn a private cloud, you create a cloud environment in your own datacenter and provide self-service access to compute resources to users in your organization.\nThis offers a simulation of a public cloud to your users, but you remain completely responsible for the purchase and maintenance of the hardware and software services you provide.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "39",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "What are two characteristics of the public cloud? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. dedicated hardware\nB. unsecured connections\nC. limited storage\nD. metered pricing\nE. self-service management",
        "answer": "DE",
        "explanation": "With the public cloud, you get pay-as-you-go pricing ג€\" you pay only for what you use, no CapEx costs.\nWith the public cloud, you have self-service management. You are responsible for the deployment and configuration of the cloud resources such as virtual machines or web sites. The underlying hardware that hosts the cloud resources is managed by the cloud provider.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: You don't have dedicated hardware. The underlying hardware is shared so you could have multiple customers using cloud resources hosted on the same physical hardware.\nB: Connections to the public cloud are secure.\nC: Storage is not limited. You can have as much storage as you like.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "40",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "When planning to migrate a public website to Azure, you must plan to :\nA. deploy a VPN\nB. pay monthly usage costs\nC. pay to transfer all the website data to Azure\nD. reduce the number of connections to the website",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "When migrating a public website to Azure, you need to plan for the pricing model that Azure provides. Azure charges for the usage of resources such as virtual machines, storage, and data transfer. Therefore, you need to plan to pay monthly usage costs for hosting the website on Azure. Deploying a VPN, paying to transfer all the website data to Azure, or reducing the number of connections to the website are not necessarily required for migrating a public website to Azure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "41",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create an Azure App Service and Azure SQL databases.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure App Service and Azure SQL databases are examples of Azure PaaS solutions. Therefore, this solution does meet the goal.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "42",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create an Azure App Service and Azure virtual machines that have Microsoft SQL Server installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "VM installed with Azure SQL fall under IaaS user will have OS access.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "43",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYour company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create an Azure App Service and Azure Storage accounts.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure App Service is a PaaS but Azure Storage accounts is not a service.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "44",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company hosts an accounting application named App1 that is used by all the customers of the company.\nApp1 has low usage during the first three weeks of each month and very high usage during the last week of each month.\nWhich benefit of Azure Cloud Services supports cost management for this type of usage pattern?\nA. high availability\nB. high latency\nC. elasticity\nD. load balancing",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Elasticity in this case is the ability to provide additional compute resource when needed and reduce the compute resource when not needed to reduce costs.\nAutoscaling is an example of elasticity.\nElastic computing is the ability to quickly expand or decrease computer processing, memory and storage resources to meet changing demands without worrying about capacity planning and engineering for peak usage. Typically controlled by system monitoring tools, elastic computing matches the amount of resources allocated to the amount of resources actually needed without disrupting operations. With cloud elasticity, a company avoids paying for unused capacity or idle resources and doesn't have to worry about investing in the purchase or maintenance of additional resources and equipment.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "45",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to migrate a web application to Azure. The web application is accessed by external users.\nYou need to recommend a cloud deployment solution to minimize the amount of administrative effort used to manage the web application.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. Software as a Service (SaaS)\nB. Platform as a Service (PaaS)\nC. Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)\nD. Database as a Service (DaaS)",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "The best option would be B. Platform as a Service (PaaS).\nPaaS provides a platform with a runtime environment for applications. It includes infrastructure, middleware, development tools, business intelligence (BI) services, database management systems, etc. The advantage of PaaS is that it allows developers to focus on coding the application without worrying about infrastructure management. This can significantly reduce the administrative effort needed to manage the web application.\nPlease note that while SaaS, IaaS, and DaaS also provide cloud services, they don’t offer the same level of management ease for a web application as PaaS does. SaaS is typically end-user applications run by third-party providers. IaaS provides only the base infrastructure, and DaaS is specifically for databases.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "46",
        "choices": "ABCDEF",
        "question": "Azure VM :\nA. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n\nAzure SQL Database :\nD. IaaS\nE. PaaS\nF. SaaS",
        "answer": "AE",
        "explanation": "Azure virtual machines are Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS).\nInfrastructure as a Service is the most flexible category of cloud services. It aims to give you complete control over the hardware that runs your application (IT infrastructure servers and virtual machines (VMs), storage, networks, and operating systems). Instead of buying hardware, with IaaS, you rent it.\n\nAzure SQL databases are Platform as a Service (Paas).\nAzure SQL Database is a fully managed Platform as a Service (PaaS) Database Engine that handles most of the database management functions such as upgrading, patching, backups, and monitoring without user involvement. Azure SQL Database is always running on the latest stable version of SQL Server\nDatabase Engine and patched OS with 99.99% availability. PaaS capabilities that are built-in into Azure SQL database enable you to focus on the domain specific database administration and optimization activities that are critical for your business.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "47",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You have an on-premises network that contains 100 servers.\nYou need to recommend a solution that provides additional resources to your users. The solution must minimize capital and operational expenditure costs.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. a complete migration to the public cloud\nB. an additional data center\nC. a private cloud\nD. a hybrid cloud",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Hybrid Cloud. \"additional resources\" is the keyword. The investment (capital expenditure) for the on-premises datacenter is already made. So continue to take advantage of it. But for additional resources it is interesting to dynamically scale in the public cloud.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "48",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- To achieve a hybrid cloud model, a company must always migrate from a private cloud model. (Y/N)\n- A company can extend the capacity of its internal network by using the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- In a public cloud model, only guest users at your company can access the resources in the cloud. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYN",
        "explanation": "No - It is not true that a company must always migrate from a private cloud model to implement a hybrid cloud. You could start with a public cloud and then combine that with an on-premise infrastructure to implement a hybrid cloud.\n\nYes - A company can extend the capacity of its internal network by using the public cloud. This is very common. When you need more capacity, rather than pay out for new on-premises infrastructure, you can configure a cloud environment and connect your on-premises network to the cloud environment by using a VPN.\n\nNo - It is not true that only guest users can access cloud resources. You can give anyone with an account in Azure Active Directory access to the cloud resources.\nThere are many authentication scenarios but a common one is to replicate your on-premises Active Directory accounts to Azure Active Directory and provide access to the Azure Active Directory accounts. Another commonly used authentication method is 'Federation' where authentication for access to cloud resources is passed to",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "49",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to migrate several servers from an on-premises network to Azure.\nWhat is an advantage of using a public cloud service for the servers over an on-premises network?\nA. The public cloud is owned by the public, NOT a private corporation\nB. The public cloud is a crowd-sourcing solution that provides corporations with the ability to enhance the cloud\nC. All public cloud resources can be freely accessed by every member of the public\nD. The public cloud is a shared entity whereby multiple corporations each use a portion of the resources in the cloud",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "The public cloud is a shared entity whereby multiple corporations each use a portion of the resources in the cloud. The hardware resources (servers, infrastructure etc.) are managed by the cloud provider. Multiple companies create resources such as virtual machines and virtual networks on the hardware resources.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: The public cloud is not owned by the public. In the case of Microsoft Azure, the cloud is owned by Microsoft.\nB: The public cloud is a not crowd-sourcing solution. In the case of Microsoft Azure, the cloud is owned by Microsoft.\nC: It is not true that public cloud resources can be freely accessed by every member of the public. You pay for a cloud subscription and create accounts for your users to access your cloud resources. No one can access your cloud resources until you create user accounts and provide the appropriate access permissions.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "50",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Azure Site Recovery provides […] for virtual machines.\nA. fault tolerance\nB. disaster recovery\nC. elasticity\nD. high availability",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure Site Recovery helps ensure business continuity by keeping business apps and workloads running during outages. Site Recovery replicates workloads running on physical and virtual machines (VMs) from a primary site to a secondary location.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "51",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "In which type of cloud model are all the hardware resources owned by a third-party and shared between multiple tenants?\nA. private\nB. hybrid\nC. public",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services and Google Cloud are three examples of public cloud services.\nMicrosoft, Amazon and Google own the hardware. The tenants are the customers who use the public cloud services.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "52",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "[…] is a desktop and application virtualization service that enables the use of a cloud-hosted version of Windows fron any location.\nA. An availability set\nB. Azure Spot Virtual Machines\nC. Azure Virtual Desktop \nD. Azure VM scale sets",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Azure Virtual Desktop, formerly known as Windows Virtual Desktop, is a Microsoft Azure-based system for virtualizing its Windows operating systems, providing virtualized desktops and applications securely in the cloud. It is aimed at enterprise customers rather than at individual users.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "53",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You have 1,000 virtual machines hosted on the Hyper-V hosts in a data center.\nYou plan to migrate all the virtual machines to an Azure pay-as-you-go subscription.\nYou need to identify which expenditure model to use for the planned Azure solution.\nWhich expenditure model should you identify?\nA. operational\nB. elastic\nC. capital\nD. scalable",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "The expenditure models are either CapEx or OpEx (Capital or Operational). CapEx is what you pay upfront, on prem, for servers, racks, cooling, security, the Datacenter itself. OpEx is what you pay to keep your infrastructure operational, like IT staff. In this case, when you move to the Cloud, what you identify in this case is the OpEx or Operational model. This is because you actually don't have CapEx on the Cloud (or at least you look to minimize CapEx) as you pay for the resources you use and not for the underlying hardware, security, cooling, etc that you will pay for in an On-Prem solution. That is why the right answer is (A) Operational. Elastic and Scalable are not expenditure models.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "54",
        "choices": "ABCD1234",
        "question": "Match the Azure services benefits to the correct descriptions.\nA. Disaster recovery \nB. Fault tolerance\nC. Low latency\nD. Dynamic scalability\n1. A cloud service that remains available after a failure occurs\n2. A cloud service that can be recovered after a failure occurs \n3. A cloud service that performs quickly when demand increases\n4. A cloud service that can be accessed quickly from the internet",
        "answer": "A2B1C4D3",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Fault tolerance is the ability of a service to remain available after a failure of one of the components of the service. For example, a service running on multiple servers can withstand the failure of one of the servers.\nBox 2: Disaster recovery is the recovery of a service after a failure. For example, restoring a virtual machine from backup after a virtual machine failure.\nBox 3: Dynamic scalability is the ability for compute resources to be added to a service when the service is under heavy load. For example, in a virtual machine scale set, additional instances of the virtual machine are added when the existing virtual machines are under heavy load.\nBox 4: Latency is the time a service to respond to requests. For example, the time it takes for a web page to be returned from a web server. Low latency means low response time which means a quicker response.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "55",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- To implement a hybrid cloud model, a company must have an internal network. (Y/N)\n- A company can extend the capacity of its internal network by using the hybrid cloud. (Y/N)\n- In a public cloud model, only guest users at your company can access the resources in the cloud. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYN",
        "explanation": "A hybrid cloud could combine a public cloud and a private cloud running on-premises or on the edge. It could also combine a public cloud with another public cloud (a.k.a., multicloud).\nHybrid models are meant to allow an organization to mix and match environments and to choose what works best for the specific applications and data. For instance, hybrid solutions are popular with companies in highly regulated industries that have strict data privacy requirements for how they store, process, and interact with their data.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "56",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A PaaS provides full control of operating systems that host applications. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS provides additional memory to apps by changing pricing tiers. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS can automatically scale the number of instances. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNY",
        "explanation": "In Azure, increasing the memory allocated to a Platform as a Service (PaaS) solution, such as an Azure App Service, is typically not achieved by changing the pricing tier. Pricing tiers for PaaS services like Azure App Service primarily affect the CPU, storage, and other resource allocations, but not the memory.\nTo adjust the memory allocated to an Azure PaaS service, you typically need to choose a different service plan or instance size within the same pricing tier. Azure App Service plans, for example, come in various sizes, each with a specific combination of CPU, memory, and other resources. By selecting a different service plan or instance size, you can increase or decrease the memory available to your application.\nSo, while changing the pricing tier can affect the overall performance and resource allocation for a PaaS solution, including CPU and storage, adjusting the memory allocation typically involves selecting the right App Service Plan or instance size within the chosen tier.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "57",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "Your company has an on-premises network that contains multiple servers.\nThe company plans to reduce the following administrative responsibilities:\n- Backing up application data\n- Replacing failed server hardware\n- Managing physical server security\n- Updating server operating systems\n- Managing permissions to shared documents\nThe company plans to migrate servers to Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to identify which administrative responsibilities will be eliminated after the planned migration.\nWhich two responsibilities should you identify? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Replacing failed server hardware\nB. Backing up application data\nC. Managing physical server security\nD. Updating server operating systems\nE. Managing permissions to shared documents",
        "answer": "AC",
        "explanation": "Azure virtual machines run on Hyper-V physical servers. The physical servers are owned and managed by Microsoft. As an Azure customer, you have no access to the physical servers. Microsoft manage the replacement of failed server hardware and the security of the physical servers so you don't need to.\nIncorrect Answers:\nB: Microsoft have no control over the applications you run on the virtual machines. Therefore, it is your responsibility to ensure that application data is backed up.\nD: Microsoft do not manage the operating systems you run on the virtual machines. Therefore, it is your responsibility to ensure that the operating systems are updated.\nE: Microsoft have no control over the shared folders you host on the virtual machines. Therefore, it is your responsibility to ensure that folder permissions are configured appropriately.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "58",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Pay-As-You-Go is an example of CapEx. (Y/N)\n- Paying electricity for your datacenter is an example of OpEx. (Y/N)\n- Deploying your own datacenter is an example of CapEx. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "Azure Pay-As-You-Go is considered an operational expense (OpEx) because it's a variable cost depending on the services used. \nPaying for electricity is indeed an operating expense since it's a regular, ongoing cost of running your datacenter. \nDeploying your own datacenter involves substantial upfront investment in physical assets, making it a capital expenditure (CapEx).\nOpEx (Operating Expenses): Expenses related to the day-to-day functioning of a business, such as rent, utilities, and maintenance costs.\nCapEx (Capital Expenditures): Large investments in goods that will be used over the long term, such as purchasing machinery, buildings, or hardware.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "59",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to provision Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) resources in Azure.\nWhich resource is an example of IaaS?\nA. an Azure web app\nB. an Azure virtual machine\nC. an Azure logic app\nD. an Azure SQL database",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "An Azure virtual machine is an example of Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS).\nAzure web app, Azure logic app and Azure SQL database are all examples of Platform as a Service (Paas).",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "60",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "To which cloud models can you deploy physical servers?\nA. private cloud and hybrid cloud only\nB. private cloud only\nC. private cloud, hybrid cloud and public cloud\nD. hybrid cloud only",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "A private cloud is on-premises so you can deploy physical servers.\nA hybrid cloud is a mix of on-premise and public cloud resources. You can deploy physical servers on-premises.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "61",
        "choices": "ABC123",
        "question": "Match the cloud model to the correct advantage.\nA. Hybrid Cloud\nB. Private Cloud\nC. Public Cloud\n1. No required capital expenditure\n2. Provides complete control over security\n3. Provides a choice to use on-premises or cloud-based resources",
        "answer": "A3B2C1",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Public Cloud -\nWith a public cloud, there is no capital expenditure on server hardware etc. You only pay for cloud resources that you use as you use them.\n\nBox 2: Private Cloud -\nA private cloud exists on premises, so you have complete control over security.\n\nBox 3: Hybrid Cloud -\nA hybrid cloud is a mix of public cloud resources and on-premises resources. Therefore, you have a choice to use either.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "62",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A company can extend a private cloud by adding its own physical servers to the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- To build a hybrid cloud, you must deploy resources to the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- A private cloud must be disconnected from the internet. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nYou cannot add physical servers to the public cloud. You can only deploy virtual servers in the public cloud. You can extend a private cloud by deploying virtual servers in a public cloud. This would create a hybrid cloud.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nA hybrid cloud is a combination of a private cloud and public cloud. Therefore, to create a hybrid cloud, you must deploy resources to a public cloud.\n\nBox 3: No.\nIt is not true that a private cloud must be disconnected from the Internet. Private clouds can be and most commonly are connected to the Internet. ג€Private cloudג€ means that the physical servers are managed by you. It does not mean that it is disconnected from the Internet.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "63",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "You have 50 virtual machines hosted on-premises and 50 virtual machines hosted in Azure. The on-premises virtual machines and the Azure virtual machines connect to each other.\nWhich type of cloud model is this?\nA. hybrid\nB. private\nC. public",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "A hybrid cloud is a mix of public cloud resources and on-premises resources. Therefore, you have a choice to use either.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "64",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A PaaS that hosts web apps in Azure provides full control of the operating systems that host applications. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS that hosts web apps in Azure can be provided with additionnal memory by changing the pricing tier. (Y/N)\n- A PaaS that hosts web apps in Azurecan be configured to automatically scale the number of instances based on demand. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nA PaaS solution does not provide access to the operating system. The Azure Web Apps service provides an environment for you to host your web applications.\nBehind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS. However, you have no direct access to the virtual machine, the operating system or IIS.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nA PaaS solution that hosts web apps in Azure does provide the ability to scale the platform automatically. This is known as autoscaling. Behind the scenes, the web apps are hosted on virtual machines running IIS. Autoscaling means adding more load balanced virtual machines to host the web apps.\nReferences:",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "65",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company migration plan.\nSolution: You create Azure virtual machines, Azure SQL databases, and Azure Storage accounts.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "N",
        "explanation": "Remember, they want ONLY PaaS. As soon as you see VM, it's an IaaS, meaning the answer to this is no. Storage account is currently still debatable but since VM is included in the suggestions, the answer is immediately No",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "66",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "Your company plans to deploy several custom applications to Azure. The applications will provide invoicing services to the customers of the company. Each application will have several prerequisite applications and services installed.\nYou need to recommend a cloud deployment solution for all the applications.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. Software as a Service (SaaS)\nB. Platform as a Service (PaaS)\nC. Infrastructure as a Service (laaS)",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "I would recommend using Platform as a Service (PaaS) for deploying the custom applications to Azure. PaaS provides a platform for developers to build, test, and deploy custom applications without having to worry about managing the underlying infrastructure. This allows developers to focus on building and deploying their applications while Azure takes care of the infrastructure management.\n\n(SaaS) – These applications are delivered over the internet and you can start using them right away.\n(PaaS) – This service provides the platform needed to build your custom app and deploy them in your infrastructure.\n(IaaS) – In this service, you rent all the infrastructure required by your organization such as virtual servers, storage, operating systems, and more.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "67",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Building a data center infrastructure is an example of OpEx. (Y/N)\n- Monthly salaries for technical personnel are an example of OpEx. (Y/N)\n- Leasing software is an example of OpEx. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nBuilding a data center infrastructure is capital expenditure, not operation expenditure.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nOpEx is ongoing costs (costs of operations) such as staff salaries.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nOpEx is ongoing costs (costs of operations) such as leasing software. If you purchased software as a one-off purchase, that would be CapEx, but leasing software is ongoing so it's OpEx.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "68",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Azure Cosmos DB is an example of a […] offering.\nA. PaaS\nB. IaaS\nC. serverless\nD. SaaS",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure Cosmos DB falls under PaaS.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "69",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- With SaaS, you must apply software updates. (Y/N)\n- With IaaS, you must install the software that you want to use. (Y/N)\n- Azure Backup is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "Azure Backup is considered a part of Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS). It's a tool that provides backup services for data in Azure. While it does provide a service, it doesn't provide a platform for developing, running, or managing applications like Platform as a Service (PaaS) does. Instead, it provides infrastructure-level capabilities, which is characteristic of IaaS. So, Azure Backup is more accurately classified as IaaS.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "70",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can create a resource group inside of another resource group. (Y/N)\n- An Azure VM can be multiple resource group. (Y/N)\n- A resource group can contain resources from multiple Azure regions. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNY",
        "explanation": "Nested Resource Groups are not allowed\nOnly One Resource Group is Necessary\nA Resource Group can contain any Region Resources",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "71",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- SQL Server 2019 installed on an Azure VM is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)\n- Azure SQL DB is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)\n- Azure Cosmo DB is an example of SaaS. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYN",
        "explanation": "AVM - Iaas \nAzure Cosmos DB - Paas \nAzure SQL Database - Pass",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "72",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You can assign a […] to every Azure resource.\nA. blueprint\nB. lock\nC. policy\nD. service endpoint",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "You can assign a policy to any scope that you have access to, such as a management group, subscription, or resource group. However, you cannot assign a policy directly to an individual resource.\nYou can assign a lock on every Azure resource that you have access to. You can apply a lock at different levels of scope: subscription, resource group, or individual resource.\nSo, the right answer is \"Lock\"!",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "73",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company plans to migrate all its data and resources to Azure.\nThe company's migration plan states that only Platform as a Service (PaaS) solutions must be used in Azure.\nYou need to deploy an Azure environment that meets the company's migration plan.\nWhat should you create?\nA. Azure virtual machines, Azure SQL databases, and Azure Storage accounts.\nB. an Azure App Service and Azure virtual machines that have Microsoft SQL Server installed.\nC. an Azure App Service and Azure SQL databases.\nD. Azure storage accounts and web server in Azure virtual machines.",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "IaaS -> Azure Virtual Machine, Azure Storage Account\nPaaS -> Azure App service, Azure SQL Database, Azure Cosmos DB, Azure Synapse Analytics\nSaaS -> Outlook email, Calendar, Microsoft Office 365",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "74",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What does a customer provide in a software as a service (SaaS) model?\nA. application data\nB. data storage\nC. compute resources\nD. application software",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "A. application data- Customer provide\nB. data storage- Third party provided\nC. compute resources- Third party provided\nD. application software- Third party provided",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "75",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Files is an example of IaaS. (Y/N)\n- A DNS server that runs on a VM is an example of PaaS. (Y/N)\n- Microsoft Intune is an example of SaaS. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNY",
        "explanation": "Azure Files is a managed file storage service, which is typically considered a Platform as a Service (PaaS) offering. A DNS server running on a VM is closer to Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS), as you manage the VM itself. Microsoft Intune, a cloud-based service in the enterprise mobility management (EMM) space, is indeed Software as a Service (SaaS), where customers use the software without managing the underlying infrastructure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "76",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Cloud Computing provides elastic scalability. (Y/N)\n- Customers can minimize CapEx by using a public cloud. (Y/N)\n- Cloud computing leverages virtualization to provide services to multiple customers simultaneously. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "YYY",
        "explanation": "Answer is YYY.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "77",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What is the first stage in the Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework for Azure?\nA. Adopt the cloud.\nB. Make a plan.\nC. Ready your organization.\nD. Define your strategy.",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Remember SPRAGM : Strategy - Plan - Ready - Adopt - Govern - Manage ",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "78",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A company can extend an internal network by adding its own physical servers to the public cloud. (Y/N)\n- A private cloud must be disconnected from the internet. (Y/N)\n- Part of a hybrid cloud is the public cloud. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNY",
        "explanation": "Answer is NNY.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "79",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You must have physical servers to use cloud computing. (Y/N)\n- You must have internet connectivity to use cloud computing. (Y/N)\n- The costs to increase cloud computing capacity are less than the costs to increase the computing capacity of an on-premises datacenter. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "Answer is NYY.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "80",
        "choices": "ABC123",
        "question": "Match the cloud model to the correct advantage.\nA. Agility\nB. Geo-Distribution\nC. Scalability\n1. Resources can be provisioned dynamically to meet demands.\n2. Applications and data can be deployed to multiple regions.\n3. Applications can be developed, tested, and launched rapidly.",
        "answer": "A3B2C1",
        "explanation": "Answer is A3B2C1.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "81",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Azure Recovery provides […] for VM.\nA. fault tolerance\nB. disaster recovery\nC. elasticity\nD. high availability",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "82",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "You plan to use Azure to host two apps named App1 and App2. The apps must meet the following requirements:\n- You must be able to modify the code of App1.\n- Administrative effort to manage the operating system of App1 must be minimized.\n- App2 must run interactively with the operating system of the server.\n\nA. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n\nApp1 and App2 ?",
        "answer": "BA",
        "explanation": "App1: You must be able to modify the code of App1, which implies a need for control over the operating system and software stack. Administrative effort to manage the operating system of App1 must be minimized, indicating a desire for platform management. Therefore, for App1, you should use Platform as a Service (PaaS). PaaS allows you to focus on your application code while abstracting away the underlying operating system management. \n\nApp2: App2 must run interactively with the operating system of the server, which implies that you need direct access to and control over the operating system. In this case, you should use Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS). IaaS provides virtual machines (VMs) where you have full control over the operating system and can run applications interactively with it.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "83",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "You have an accounting application named App1 that uses a legacy database.\nYou plan to move App1 to the cloud.\nWhich service model should you use?\nA. platform as a service (PaaS)\nB. infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nC. software as a service (SaaS)",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "App1 to the cloud is infrastructure as a service (IaaS). The reason for this is that IaaS allows you to have greater control over the operating system, networking, and other infrastructure components, which is important when you're working with legacy applications. With IaaS, you can still use your legacy database and other existing components, while taking advantage of the scalability and cost savings offered by cloud infrastructure. Platform as a service (PaaS) and software as a service (SaaS) are not ideal for legacy applications as they may require extensive modifications to the code or may not be compatible with the existing infrastructure. PaaS may be suitable if the application can be easily refactored or modernized to work on a new platform, while SaaS is most appropriate for applications where you don't have control over the underlying infrastructure or code.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "84",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "When you are implementing a SaaS solution, you are responsible for :\nA. configuring high availability\nB. defining scalability rules\nC. installing the SaaS solution\nD. configuring the SaaS solution",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Software as a service (or SaaS) is a way of delivering applications over the Internetג€\"as a service. Instead of installing and maintaining software, you simply access it via the Internet, freeing yourself from complex software and hardware management.\nSaaS applications are sometimes called Web-based software, on-demand software, or hosted software. Whatever the name, SaaS applications run on a SaaS provider's servers. The provider manages access to the application, including security, availability, and performance.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "85",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "An Azure web app that queries an on-premises Microsoft SQL server is an example of […] cloud.\nA. hybrid\nB. multi-vendor\nC. private\nD. public",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Answer is A.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "86",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "A Microsoft SQL Server database that is hosted in the cloud and has software updates managed by Azure in an example of […].\nA. DRaaS\nB. IaaS\nC. PaaS\nD. SaaS",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Platform as a service (PaaS) is a complete development and deployment environment in the cloud, with resources that enable you to deliver everything from simple cloud-based apps to sophisticated, cloud-enabled enterprise applications. You purchase the resources you need from a cloud service provider on a pay- as-you-go basis and access them over a secure Internet connection.\nLike IaaS, PaaS includes infrastructure \"servers, storage, and networking\"but also middleware, development tools, business intelligence (BI) services, database management systems, and more.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "87",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "Which cloud computing model includes on-premises and cloud-based resources?\nA. hybrid\nB. public\nC. private",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Answer is A.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "88",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Autoscaling is an example of […].\nA. agility\nB. elasticity\nC. geo-distribution\nD. predictability",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Autoscaling takes advantage of the elasticity of cloud-hosted environments while easing management overhead. It reduces the need for an operator to continually monitor the performance of a system and make decisions about adding or removing resources.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "89",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "[…] supports synchronization between on-premises storage and Azure Storage.\nA. Azure Blob Storage\nB. Azure Files\nC. Azure Queue Storage\nD. Azure Table Storage",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "90",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Which term represents the ability to increase the computing capacity of a virtual machine by adding memory or CPUs?\nA. agility\nB. vertical scaling\nC. horizontal scaling\nD. elasticity",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Vertical scaling, also known as scale up and scale down, means increasing or decreasing virtual machine (VM) sizes in response to a workload. Compare this behavior with horizontal scaling, also referred to as scale out and scale in, where the number of VMs is altered depending on the workload.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "91",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What are two benefits of cloud computing? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. enables the rapid provisioning of resources\nB. has increased administrative complexity\nC. has the same configuration options as on-premises\nD. shifts capital expenditures (CAPEX) to operating expenditures (OPEX)",
        "answer": "AD",
        "explanation": "Azure allows you to build, deploy, and manage apps more quickly and easily without having to buy and/or maintain the underlying infrastructure.\nAzure provides flexibility between CapEx and OpEx\nCapital expenditures generate benefits over a long period. These expenditures are generally nonrecurring and result in the acquisition of permanent assets.\nBuilding an application could qualify as a capital expenditure. Example, Azure Reserved Instances (Azure RI) help Azure's most active customers save on long- term VM usage reserving VMs in advance at a discounted price by committing to a one or three-year benefits.\nOperating expenditures are ongoing costs of doing business. Consuming cloud services in a pay-as-you-go model could qualify as an operating expenditure.\nExample, you pay for a service or product as you use it i.e. pay-as-you-go pricing.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "92",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What is a feature of an Azure virtual network?\nA. resource cost analysis\nB. packet inspection\nC. geo-redundancy\nD. isolation and segmentation",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Azure Virtual Network (VNet) is the fundamental building block for your private network in Azure. VNet enables many types of Azure resources, such as Azure Virtual Machines (VM), to securely communicate with each other, the internet, and on-premises networks. VNet is similar to a traditional network that you'd operate in your own data center, but brings with it additional benefits of Azure's infrastructure such as scale, availability, and isolation.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "93",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "[…] enables Azure resources to be deployed close to users.\nA. Elasticity\nB. Geo-distribution\nC. High-Availability\nD. Scalability",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Geo-distribution makes you deploy apps and data to regional datacenters around the globe that is close to your customer to ensure best performance.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "94",
        "choices": "ABCD123",
        "question": "A. Disaster recovery\nB. Geo-Distribution\nC. High Availability\nD. Scalability \n1. Increase the compute capacity of apps in the cloud\n2. Provide a continuous user experience with no apparent downtime\n3. Ensures that users always have the best experience by deploying apps to all the regions where there are users",
        "answer": "B3C2D1",
        "explanation": "Answer is B3C2D1.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "95",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Which cloud computing benefit provides continuous user access to a cloud-based application with minimal downtime?\nA. agility\nB. scalability\nC. elasticity\nD. high availability",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Answer is D.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "96",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You need to identify the type of failure for which an Azure Availability Zone can be used to protect access to Azure services.\nWhat should you identify?\nA. a physical server failure\nB. an Azure region failure\nC. a storage failure\nD. an Azure data center failure",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "It seems that in these questions designed by Microsoft it always follows this thinking pattern:\nRegions > Zones > Data Center.\nWhen you see a question like this with the keyword Zone AUTOMATICALLY you think protecting or managing data centers!",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "97",
        "choices": "ABCDEFGH",
        "question": "You plan to extend your company's network to Azure.\nThe network contains a VPN appliance that uses an IP address of 131.107.200.1.\nYou need to create an Azure resource that defines the VPN appliance in Azure.\nWhich Azure resource should you create?\nA. NAT gateways\nB. Application gateways\nC. Local network gateways\nD. Virtual network gateways\nE. On-premises Data Gateways\nF. Azure Data Box Gateway\nG. Azure Stack Edge / Data Box Gateway\nH. Web Application Firewall policies",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "A Local Network Gateway is an object in Azure that represents your on-premise VPN device. A Virtual Network Gateway is the VPN object at the Azure end of the VPN. A 'connection' is what connects the Local Network Gateway and the Virtual Network Gateway to bring up the VPN.\nThe local network gateway typically refers to your on-premises location. You give the site a name by which Azure can refer to it, then specify the IP address of the on-premises VPN device to which you will create a connection. You also specify the IP address prefixes that will be routed through the VPN gateway to the VPN device. The address prefixes you specify are the prefixes located on your on-premises network. If your on-premises network changes or you need to change the public IP address for the VPN device, you can easily update the values later.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "98",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more resource groups.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Resource groups has never been a fault tolerance approach, resource groups are used to easy manage a group of resources.\nIt is a logical container for Azure resources. When you create a resource group, you specify which location to create the resource group in.\nHowever, when you create a virtual machine and place it in the resource group, the virtual machine can still be in a different location (different datacenter).\nTherefore, creating multiple resource groups, even if they are in separate datacenters does not ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "99",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to a scale set.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "This answer does not specify that the scale set will be configured across multiple data centers so this solution does not meet the goal.\nAzure virtual machine scale sets let you create and manage a group of load balanced VMs. The number of VM instances can automatically increase or decrease in response to demand or a defined schedule. Scale sets provide high availability to your applications, and allow you to centrally manage, configure, and update many VMs.\nVirtual machines in a scale set can be deployed across multiple update domains and fault domains to maximize availability and resilience to outages due to data center outages, and planned or unplanned maintenance events.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "100",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure subscription can be associated to multiple Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenants.. (Y/N)\n- You can change the Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenant to which an Azure subscription is associated. (Y/N)\n- When an Azure subscription expires, the associated Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenant is deleted automatically. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYN",
        "explanation": "An Azure AD tenant can have multiple subscriptions but an Azure subscription can only be associated with one Azure AD tenant.\n\nIf your subscription expires, you lose access to all the other resources associated with the subscription. However, the Azure AD directory remains in Azure. You can associate and manage the directory using a different Azure subscription.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "101",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Resource groups provide organizations with the ability to manage the compliance of Azure resources across multiple subscriptions.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed\nB. Management groups\nC. Azure policies\nD. Azure App Service plans",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "If your organization has many Azure subscriptions, you may need a way to efficiently manage access, policies, and compliance for those subscriptions. Management groups provide a governance scope above subscriptions. You organize subscriptions into management groups; the governance conditions you apply cascade by inheritance to all associated subscriptions.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "102",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "The company has several departments. All the Azure resources used by each department will be managed by a department administrator.\nWhat are two possible techniques to segment Azure for the departments? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. multiple subscriptions\nB. multiple Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) directories\nC. multiple regions\nD. multiple resource groups",
        "answer": "AD",
        "explanation": "An Azure subscription is a container for Azure resources. It is also a boundary for permissions to resources and for billing. You are charged monthly for all resources in a subscription. A single Azure tenant (Azure Active Directory) can contain multiple Azure subscriptions.\nA resource group is a container that holds related resources for an Azure solution. The resource group can include all the resources for the solution, or only those resources that you want to manage as a group.\nTo enable each department administrator to manage the Azure resources used by that department, you will need to create a separate subscription per department. You can then assign each department administrator as an administrator for the subscription to enable them to manage all resources in that subscription.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "103",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A single Microsoft account can be used to manage Azure multiple subscriptions. (Y/N)\n- Two Azure subscriptions can be merged into a single subscription. (Y/N)\n- A company can use resources from multiple subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "YNY",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nYou can use the same account to manage multiple subscriptions. You can create an additional subscription for your account in the Azure portal. You may want an additional subscription to avoid hitting subscription limits, to create separate environments for security, or to isolate data for compliance reasons.\n\nBox 2: No -\nYou cannot merge two subscriptions into a single subscription. However, you can move some Azure resources from one subscription to another. You can also transfer ownership of a subscription and change the billing type for a subscription.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nA company can have multiple subscriptions and store resources in the different subscriptions. However, a resource instance can exist in only one subscription.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "104",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You have several VM in an Azure subscription. You create a new subscription :\nA. The VM cannot be moved to the new subscription.\nB. The VM can be moved to the new subscription.\nC. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run all in the same resource group.\nD. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run Windows Server 2016.\n",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "You can move a VM and its associated resources to a different subscription by using the Azure portal.\nMoving between subscriptions can be handy if you originally created a VM in a personal subscription and now want to move it to your company's subscription to continue your work. You do not need to start the VM in order to move it and it should continue to run during the move.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "105",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "You have an Azure environment that contains multiple Azure virtual machines.\nYou plan to implement a solution that enables the client computers on your on-premises network to communicate to the Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to recommend which Azure resources must be created for the planned solution.\nWhich two Azure resources should you include in the recommendation? Each correct answer presents part of the solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. a virtual network gateway\nB. a load balancer\nC. an application gateway\nD. a virtual network\nE. a gateway subnet",
        "answer": "AE",
        "explanation": "Having a virtual network is necessary but not sufficient; You need a subnet to host you VPN Gateway which is called a gateway subnet.\nA gateway subnet is necessary AND sufficient, because if you want to create a gateway subnet you need to a VNet which is implied. so AE.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "106",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You attempt to create several managed Microsoft SQL Server instances in an Azure environment and receive a message that you must increase your Azure subscription limits.\nWhat should you do to increase the limits?\nA. Create a service health alert\nB. Upgrade your support plan\nC. Modify an Azure policy\nD. Create a new support request",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Many Azure resource have quote limits. The purpose of the quota limits is to help you control your Azure costs. However, it is common to require an increase to the default quota.\nYou can request a quota limit increase by opening a support request. In the support request, select 'Service and subscription limits (quotas)' for the Issue type, select your subscription and the service you want to increase the quota for. For this question, you would select 'SQL Database Managed Instance' as the quote type.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "107",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Each Azure subscription can contain multiple account administrators. (Y/N)\n- Each Azure subscription can be managed by using a Microsoft account only. (Y/N)\n- An Azure resource group contains multiple Azure subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nYou can assign service administrators and co-administrators in the Azure Portal but there can only be one account administrator.\n\nBox 2: No -\nYou need an Azure Active Directory account to manage a subscription, not a Microsoft account.\nAn account is created in the Azure Active Directory when you create the subscription. Further accounts can be created in the Azure Active Directory to manage the subscription.\n\nBox 3: No -\nResource groups are logical containers for Azure resources. However, resource groups do not contain subscriptions. Subscriptions contain resource groups.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "108",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Availability zones can be implemented in all Azure regions. (Y/N)\n- Only VM that run Windows Server can be created in availability zones. (Y/N)\n- Availability zones are used to replicate data and applications to multiple regions. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nNot all Azure regions support availability zones.\n\nBox 2: No -\nAvailability zones can be used with many Azure services, not just VMs.\n\nBox 3: No -\nAvailability Zones are unique physical locations within a single Azure region.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "109",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to create an Azure virtual machine.\nYou need to identify which storage service must be used to store the unmanaged data disks of the virtual machine.\nA. Containers : Scalable, cost-effective for unstructured data.\nB. File shares : Serverless SMB files shares.\nC. Tables : Tabular data storage.\nD. Queues : Effectively scale apps according to traffic.",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure containers are the backbone of the virtual disks platform for Azure IaaS. Both Azure OS and data disks are implemented as virtual disks where data is durably persisted in the Azure Storage platform and then delivered to the virtual machines for maximum performance. Azure Disks are persisted in Hyper-V VHD format and stored as a page blob in Azure Storage.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "110",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company plans to move several servers to Azure.\nThe company's compliance policy states that a server named FinServer must be on a separate network segment.\nYou are evaluating which Azure services can be used to meet the compliance policy requirements.\nWhich Azure solution should you recommend?\nA. a resource group for FinServer and another resource group for all the other servers\nB. a virtual network for FinServer and another virtual network for all the other servers\nC. a VPN for FinServer and a virtual network gateway for each other server\nD. one resource group for all the servers and a resource lock for FinServer",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure virtual networks provide the 'Isolation and segmentation' networking capability.\nNetworks in Azure are known as virtual networks. A virtual network can have multiple IP address spaces and multiple subnets. Azure automatically routes traffic between different subnets within a virtual network.\nThe question states that FinServer must be on a separate network segment. The only way to separate FinServer from the other servers in networking terms is to place the server in a different virtual network to the other servers.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "111",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to map a network drive from several computers that run Windows 10 to Azure Storage.\nYou need to create a storage solution in Azure for the planned mapped drive.\nWhat should you create?\nA. an Azure SQL database\nB. a virtual machine data disk\nC. a File service in a storage account\nD. a Blob service in a storage account",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Azure Files is Microsoft's easy-to-use cloud file system. Azure file shares can be seamlessly used in Windows and Windows Server.\nTo use an Azure file share with Windows, you must either mount it, which means assigning it a drive letter or mount point path, or access it via its UNC path.\nUnlike other SMB shares you may have interacted with, such as those hosted on a Windows Server, Linux Samba server, or NAS device, Azure file shares do not currently support Kerberos authentication with your Active Directory (AD) or Azure Active Directory (AAD) identity, although this is a feature we are working on.\nInstead, you must access your Azure file share with the storage account key for the storage account containing your Azure file share. A storage account key is an administrator key for a storage account, including administrator permissions to all files and folders within the file share you're accessing, and for all file shares and other storage resources (blobs, queues, tables, etc) contained within your storage account.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "112",
        "choices": "ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOP",
        "question": "You plan to implement an Azure database solution.\nYou need to implement a database solution that meets the following requirements:\n- Can add data concurrently from multiple regions\n- Can store JSON documents\nWhich database service should you deploy? To answer, select the appropriate service in the answer area.\nA. Azure Cosmos DB\nB. Azure Database for MySQL servers\nC. Azure Database for MariaDB servers\nD. SQL Data warehouses\nE. Azure Cache for Redis\nF. Data factories\nG. Virtual Clusters\nH. Elastic Job agents\nI. SQL databases\nJ. Azure Database for PostgreSQL servers\nK. SQL servers\nL. Azure Database Migration Services\nM. SQL Server stretch databases\nN. SQL elastic pools\nO. Managed databases\nP. SQL managed instances",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure Cosmos DB is Microsoft's globally distributed, multi-model database service. With a click of a button, Cosmos DB enables you to elastically and independently scale throughput and storage across any number of Azure regions worldwide.\nAzure Cosmos DB is a great way to store unstructured and JSON data. Combined with Azure Functions, Cosmos DB makes storing data quick and easy with much less code than required for storing data in a relational database.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "113",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company plans to start using Azure and will migrate all its network resources to Azure.\nYou need to start the planning process by exploring Azure.\nWhat should you create first?\nA. a subscription\nB. a resource group\nC. a virtual network\nD. a management group",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "The first thing you create in Azure is a subscription. You can think of an Azure subscription as an 'Azure account'. You get billed per subscription.\nA subscription is an agreement with Microsoft to use one or more Microsoft cloud platforms or services, for which charges accrue based on either a per-user license fee or on cloud-based resource consumption.\n- Microsoft's Software as a Service (SaaS)-based cloud offerings (Office 365, Intune/EMS, and Dynamics 365) charge per-user license fees.\n- Microsoft's Platform as a Service (PaaS) and Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) cloud offerings (Azure) charge based on cloud resource consumption.\nYou can also use a trial subscription, but the subscription expires after a specific amount of time or consumption charges. You can convert a trial subscription to a paid subscription.\nOrganizations can have multiple subscriptions for Microsoft's cloud offerings.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "114",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- All the Azure resources deployed to a resource group must use the same Azure region. (Y/N)\n- If you assign a tag to a resource group, all the Azure resources in that resource group are assigned to the same tag. (Y/N)\n- If you assign permissions for a user to manage a resource group, the user can manage all the Azure resources in that resource group. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNY",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure resources deployed to a single resource group can be located in different regions. The resource group only contains metadata about the resources it contains.\nWhen creating a resource group, you need to provide a location for that resource group. You may be wondering, \"Why does a resource group need a location?\nAnd, if the resources can have different locations than the resource group, why does the resource group location matter at all?\" The resource group stores metadata about the resources. When you specify a location for the resource group, you're specifying where that metadata is stored. For compliance reasons, you may need to ensure that your data is stored in a particular region.\n\nBox 2: No -\nTags for Resources are not inherited by default from their Resource Group\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nA resource group can be used to scope access control for administrative actions. By default, permissions set at the resource level are inherited by the resources in the resource group.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "115",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Data that is stored in the Archive access tier of an Azure Storage account […].\nA. can be accessed at any time by using azcopy.exe.\nB. can only be read by using Azure Backup.\nC. must be restored before the data can be accessed.\nD. must be rehydrated before the data can be accessed.",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Azure storage offers different access tiers: hot, cool and archive.\nThe archive access tier has the lowest storage cost. But it has higher data retrieval costs compared to the hot and cool tiers. Data in the archive tier can take several hours to retrieve.\nWhile a blob is in archive storage, the blob data is offline and can't be read, overwritten, or modified. To read or download a blob in archive, you must first rehydrate it to an online tier.\nExample usage scenarios for the archive access tier include:\n- Long-term backup, secondary backup, and archival datasets\n- Original (raw) data that must be preserved, even after it has been processed into final usable form.\n- Compliance and archival data that needs to be stored for a long time and is hardly ever accessed.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "116",
        "choices": "AA",
        "question": "The application will run on an Azure virtual machine.\nYou need to recommend a deployment solution for the application. The solution must provide a guaranteed availability of 99.99 percent.\nWhat is the minimum number of virtual machines and the minimum number of availability zones you should recommend for the deployment?\n- Minimum number of VM ? A. 1 B.2 C.3\n- Minimum number of availability zones ? A. 1 B.2 C.3",
        "answer": "BB",
        "explanation": "You need a minimum of two virtual machines with each one located in a different availability zone.\nAvailability Zones is a high-availability offering that protects your applications and data from datacenter failures. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region. Each zone is made up of one or more datacenters equipped with independent power, cooling, and networking. To ensure resiliency, there's a minimum of three separate zones in all enabled regions. The physical separation of Availability Zones within a region protects applications and data from datacenter failures. Zone-redundant services replicate your applications and data across Availability Zones to protect from single-points-of-failure. With Availability\nZones, Azure offers industry best 99.99% VM uptime SLA.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "117",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Which Azure service should you use to collect events from multiple resources into a centralized repository?\nA. Azure Event Hubs\nB. Azure Analysis Services\nC. Azure Monitor\nD. Azure Stream Analytics",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Correlate events = Azure Log Analytics\nCollect events = Azure Event Hubs\n\nThe Azure service you should use to collect events from multiple resources into a centralized repository is A. Azure Event Hubs.\nAzure Event Hubs is specifically designed as a high-throughput, real-time event ingestion service that can collect events from multiple sources. It's built to handle massive streams of data sent by application or infrastructure components in real-time. This data can then be processed by analytics services or stored for later analysis.\nOn the other hand, C. Azure Monitor is more focused on collecting operational telemetry, such as performance metrics, activity logs, and diagnostics data, to monitor the health and performance of Azure services. While Azure Monitor does collect events in the form of logs and metrics, its PRIMARY USE is NOT as an event ingestion service but as a monitoring and alerting service. Azure Event Hubs is the better choice when the goal is to set up a large-scale, event-driven data pipeline​​.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "118",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "An Availability Zone in Azure has physically separate locations […].\nA. accross two continents.\nB. within a single Azure region.\nC. within multiple Azure regions.\nD. within a single Azure datacenter.",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Availability Zones is a high-availability offering that protects your applications and data from datacenter failures. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "119",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Data that is stored in an Azure Storage account automatically has at least three copies. (Y/N)\n- All data that is copied to an Azure Storage account is backed up automatically to another Azure data center. (Y/N)\n- An Azure Storage account can contain up to 2 TB of data and up to one million files. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "YNN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nThere are different replication options available with a storage account. The 'minimum' replication option is Locally Redundant Storage (LRS). With LRS, data is replicated synchronously three times within the primary region.\n\nBox 2: No -\nData is not backed up automatically to another Azure Data Center although it can be depending on the replication option configured for the account. Locally\nRedundant Storage (LRS) is the default which maintains three copies of the data in the data center.\nGeo-redundant storage (GRS) has cross-regional replication to protect against regional outages. Data is replicated synchronously three times in the primary region, then replicated asynchronously to the secondary region.\n\nBox 3: No -\nThe limits are much higher than that. The current storage limit is 2 PB for US and Europe, and 500 TB for all other regions (including the UK) with no limit on the number of files.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "120",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- If you have Azure resources deployed to every region, you can implement availability zones in all the regions. (Y/N)\n- Only virtual machines that run Windows Server can be created in availability zones. (Y/N)\n- Availability zones are used to replicate data and applications to multiple regions. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNN",
        "explanation": "1- Not every region has multiple Availability Zone. Some regions may have only one Availability Zone.\n2- One can run both Linux and Windows virtual machines created in the availability zone.\n3- Availability zones are used to replicate data and applications in the same region.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "121",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- North America is represented by a single Azure region. (Y/N)\n- Every Azure region has multiple datacenters. (Y/N)\n- Data transfers between Azure services located in different Azure regions are always free. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nNorth America has several Azure regions, including West US, Central US, South Central US, East Us, and Canada East.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nA region is a set of datacenters deployed within a latency-defined perimeter and connected through a dedicated regional low-latency network.\n\nBox 3: No -\nOutbound data transfer is charged at the normal rate and inbound data transfer is free.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "122",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more scale sets.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "N",
        "explanation": "This answer does not specify that the scale set will be configured across multiple data centers so this solution does not meet the goal.\nAzure virtual machine scale sets let you create and manage a group of load balanced VMs. The number of VM instances can automatically increase or decrease in response to demand or a defined schedule. Scale sets provide high availability to your applications, and allow you to centrally manage, configure, and update many VMs.\nVirtual machines in a scale set can be deployed across multiple update domains and fault domains to maximize availability and resilience to outages due to data center outages, and planned or unplanned maintenance events.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "123",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You need to be notified when Microsoft plans to perform maintenance that can affect the resources deployed to an Azure subscription.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure Monitor\nB. Azure Service Health\nC. Azure Advisor\nD. Microsoft Trust Center",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure Service Health provides a personalized view of the health of the Azure services and regions you're using. This is the best place to look for service impacting communications about outages, planned maintenance activities, and other health advisories because the authenticated Service Health experience knows which services and resources you currently use.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "124",
        "choices": "ABC123",
        "question": "A. Azure Sphere\nB. IoT Central\nC. IoT Hub\n1. A software and hardware solution that provides communication and security features for IoT devices\n2. A fully managed software as a service (SaaS) solution to connect, monitor, and manage IoT devices at scale\n3. A managed service that provides bidirectional communication between IoT devices and Azure\n\n\n\n\n",
        "answer": "A3B2C1",
        "explanation": "hu(b) = (b)iderectional\n(c)entral = (c)onnect\n(s)phere = (s)ecurity",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "125",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- A Windows Virtual Desktop session host can run Windows 10 only. (Y/N)\n- A Windows Virtual Desktop host pool that includes 20 session hosts supports a maximum of 20 simultaneous user connections. (Y/N)\n- Windows Virtual Desktop supports desktop and app virtualization. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNY",
        "explanation": "1. NO - Supported O/Ses are Windows 10 Enterprise multi-session or Windows 10 Enterprise, Windows 7 Enterprise, Windows Server 2012 R2, 2016, 2019.\n2. NO - For Max session limit, enter the maximum number of users you want load-balanced to a single session host\n3. YES- Via RemoteApps",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "126",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "[…] can calculate cost savibgs due to reduced electricity consumption as a result of migrating on-premises Microsoft SQL servers to Azure.\nA. The Azure Migrate: Server Assessment tool\nB. The Azure Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) calculator\nC. The Database Migrating Assistant\nD. The pricing calculator in Azure",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "The Azure Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) calculator is a free online tool that allows you to estimate the cost savings you can achieve by migrating your application workloads to Microsoft Azure. It helps you to evaluate potential cost savings if you migrate on-premises application workloads to Microsoft Azure by specifying the details of your existing infrastructure and various cost assumptions you want the tool to work with. You can then receive a report that shows on-premises costs compared to Microsoft Azure costs.\n\nHere are the reasons why the other options are incorrect:\nThe pricing calculator in Azure: It is an online tool that provides estimates of the cost of Azure products and services 5. While it can help you estimate the costs for Azure products and services, it is not specifically designed to calculate cost savings due to reduced electricity consumption as a result of migrating on-premises Microsoft SQL servers to Azure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "127",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can use Availability Zones in Azure to protect Azure virtual machines from a datacenter failure. (Y/N)\n- You can use Availability Zones in Azure to protect Azure virtual machines from a region failure. (Y/N)\n- You can use Availability Zones in Azure to protect Azure managed disks from a datacenter failure. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "YNY",
        "explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. Availability Zones are unique physical locations within an Azure region. Each zone is made up of one or more datacenters equipped with independent power, cooling, and networking. To ensure resiliency, there are a minimum of three separate zones in all enabled regions. The physical separation of Availability Zones within a region protects applications and data from datacenter failures.\nWith Availability Zones, Azure offers industry best 99.99% VM uptime SLA. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your applications and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "128",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true.\nOtherwise, select No.\n- An Azure subscription can have multiple account administrators. (Y/N)\n- An Azure subscription can be managed by using a Microsoft account only. (Y/N)\n- An Azure resource group can contain multiple Azure subscriptions. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nYou can assign service administrators and co-administrators in the Azure Portal but there can only be one account administrator.\n\nBox 2: No -\nYou need an Azure Active Directory account to manage a subscription, not a Microsoft account.\nAn account is created in the Azure Active Directory when you create the subscription. Further accounts can be created in the Azure Active Directory to manage the subscription.\n\nBox 3: No -\nResource groups are logical containers for Azure resources. However, resource groups do not contain subscriptions. Subscriptions contain resource groups.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "129",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "A cloud service that supports a maximum of 20 instances is more […] than a service that supports a maximum of five instances.\nA. distributed\nB. scalable\nC. secure",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "The correct answer is scalable.\nA cloud service that supports a maximum of 20 instances is more scalable than a service that supports a maximum of five instances. Scalability refers to the ability of a system to handle increased workload by adding resources to the system. In this case, a cloud service that supports a maximum of 20 instances can handle more workload than a service that supports a maximum of five instances, making it more scalable.\nHere are the reasons why the other options are incorrect:\nDistributed: A distributed system is one in which components are located on different networked computers and communicate and coordinate their actions by passing messages. While a cloud service can be distributed, the number of instances it supports does not determine whether it is distributed or not.\nSecure: Security refers to the measures taken to protect a system from unauthorized access or attack. While security is an important aspect of cloud services, the number of instances it supports does not determine whether it is secure or not.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "130",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true.\nOtherwise, select No.\n- To use Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials to sign in to a computer that runs Windows 10, the computer must be joined to Azure AD. (Y/N)\n- Users in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) are organized by using resource groups. (Y/N)\n- Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) groups support dynamic membership rules. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "YNY",
        "explanation": "To use Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials to sign in to a computer that runs Windows 10, the computer must be joined to Azure AD. Yes, this statement is true. To use Azure AD credentials to sign in to a computer that runs Windows 10, the computer must be joined to Azure AD.\nUsers in Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) are organized by using resource groups. No, this statement is incorrect. Users in Azure AD is organized by using directories, domains, and organizational units (OUs).\nAzure Active Directory (Azure AD) groups support dynamic membership rules. Yes, this statement is true. Azure AD groups support dynamic membership rules that allow you to add or remove members based on user or device attributes.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "131",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines remain available if a single data center fails.\nWhat are two possible solutions? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nA. Deploy the virtual machines to two or more availability zones.\nB. Deploy the virtual machines to two or more resource groups.\nC. Deploy the virtual machines to a scale set.\nD. Deploy the virtual machines to two or more regions.",
        "answer": "AD",
        "explanation": "Answer is AD.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "132",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to deploy 20 VM to an Azure environment. To ensure that a VM named VM1 cannot connect to the other VM, VM1 must […].\nA. be deployed to a separate VM\nB. run a different operating system than the other VMs\nC. be deployed to a separate resource group\nD. have 2 network interfaces",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure automatically routes traffic between subnets in a virtual network. Therefore, all virtual machines in a virtual network can connect to the other virtual machines in the same virtual network. Even if the virtual machines are on separate subnets within the virtual network, they can still communicate with each other.\nTo ensure that a virtual machine cannot connect to the other virtual machines, the virtual machine must be deployed to a separate virtual network.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "133",
        "choices": "ABC123",
        "question": "A. Azure Cosmos DB\nB. Azure HDInsight\nC. Azure Synapse Analytics\n1. A fully managed data warehouse that has integral security at every level of scale at no extra cost.\n2. A globally distributed database that supports NoSQL.\n3. Managed Apache Hadoop clusters in the cloud that enable you to process massive amounts of data.",
        "answer": "A2B3C1",
        "explanation": "Azure synapse analytics = Warehouse\nAzure cosmos = even larger than the globe (global) : cosmos\nAzure HDInsight = HaDoop",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "134",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What is the most severe failure from which an Azure Availability Zone can be used to protect access to Azure service?\nA. a physical server failure\nB. an Azure region failure\nC. a storage failure\nD. an Azure data center failure",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. An Availability Zone is a physically separate zone, within an Azure region. There are three Availability Zones per supported Azure region.\nEach Availability Zone has a distinct power source, network, and cooling. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your apps and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "135",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What is the most severe failure from which an Azure Availability Zone can be used to protect access to Azure service?\nA. a physical server failure\nB. an Azure region failure\nC. a storage failure\nD. an Azure data center failure",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. An Availability Zone is a physically separate zone, within an Azure region. There are three Availability Zones per supported Azure region.\nEach Availability Zone has a distinct power source, network, and cooling. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your apps and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "136",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You need to purchase a third-party virtual security appliance that you will deploy to an Azure subscription.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure subscriptions\nB. Azure Security Center\nC. Azure Marketplace\nD. Microsoft Store",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Azure Marketplace is a digital marketplace that offers a wide range of third-party virtual appliances, including security appliances, that can be deployed to an Azure subscription.\nAzure subscriptions (option A) are used to manage access to Azure services and resources, and do not provide virtual appliances.\nAzure Security Center (option B) is a unified infrastructure security management system that provides advanced threat protection across hybrid cloud workloads. While it can help you identify and mitigate security risks, it does not offer third-party virtual appliances.\nMicrosoft Store (option D) is an online store that offers software applications, games, and other digital content for Windows devices. It does not offer third-party virtual appliances for Azure subscriptions.\nTherefore, the best option for purchasing a third-party virtual security appliance that you will deploy to an Azure subscription is C. Azure Marketplace.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "137",
        "choices": "AB12",
        "question": "A. Azure Functions\nB. Azure Logic Apps\n1. Executes code and is always stateful\n2. Runs only in the cloud",
        "answer": "A1B2",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Azure Functions -\nAzure Functions allows you to implement your system's logic into readily available blocks of code called \"functions\". Different functions can run anytime you need to respond to critical events.\nAzure Logic Apps can have multiple stateful and stateless workflows.\n\nBox 2: Azure Logic Apps -\nAzure Logic Apps is a cloud-based platform for creating and running automated workflows that integrate your apps, data, services, and systems.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "138",
        "choices": "ABCD123",
        "question": "A. Azure Blueprints\nB. Azure Policy\nC. Azure resource group\nD. Azure tags\n1. Restrict which VM types can be created in a subscrption\n2. Identify Azure resources that are associated with specific cost centers\n3. Deploy a complete Azure application environment including resources configuration and role assigments",
        "answer": "A3D2B1",
        "explanation": "Policy = Restrict\nTag = Identify\nBP = Deploy",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "139",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "An Availability Zone in Azure has physically separate locations […].\nA. accross two continents.\nB. within a single Azure region.\nC. within multiple Azure regions.\nD. within a single Azure datacenter.",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Box: within a single Azure region\nAzure availability zones are physically separate locations within each Azure region that are tolerant to local failures.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "140",
        "choices": "ABCD1234",
        "question": "A. Azure Functions\nB. Azure App Service\nC. Azure Virtual Machines\nD. Azure Container Instances\n1. Provide operating system virtualization\n2. Provide portable environment for virtualized applications\n3. Used to build, deploy, and scale web apps\n4. Provide a platform for serverless code",
        "answer": "A4B3C1D2",
        "explanation": "Easy to memorize, VM, CONTAINER = PART OF VM OS, APP = APP SERVICE , CODE = FUNCTION\n\nBox 1: Azure virtual machines -\nBox 2: Azure Container instances\nAzure Container Instances (ACI) is a managed service that allows you to run containers directly on the Microsoft Azure public cloud, without requiring the use of virtual machines (VMs).\nDevelop apps fast without managing virtual machines or having to learn new toolsג€\"it's just your application, in a container, running in the cloud.\n\nBox 3: Azure App Service -\nAzure App Service is a fully managed platform for building web applications.\nApplications run and scale with ease on both Windows and Linux-based environments.\n\nBox 4: Azure Functions -\nAzure Functions (from Microsoft Azure) is a cloud-based serverless service that allows running event-triggered code in a scalable way without providing or managing infrastructure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "141",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You have several VM in an Azure subscription. You create a new subscription :\nA. The VM cannot be moved to the new subscription.\nB. The VM can be moved to the new subscription.\nC. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run all in the same resource group\nD. The VM can be moved to the new subscription only if they run Windows Server 2019",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Box: The virtual machines can be moved to the new subscription.\nYou can move a VM and its associated resources to a different subscription by using the Azure portal.\nNote: Repeat the process below for each Resource Group containing the VMs.\n1. Go to the Azure portal to manage the resource group containing the VM to move. Search for and select Resource groups.\n2. Choose the resource group containing the VM that you would like to move.\n3. At the top of the page for the resource group, select Move and then select Move to another subscription. The Move resources page opens.\n4. Select each of the resources to move. In most cases, you should move all of the related resources that are listed.\n5. Select the Subscription where you want the VM to be moved.\n6. Select an existing Resource group, or enter a name to have a new resource group created.\n7. When you are done, select that you understand that new resource IDs will be created and that the new IDs will need to be used with the VM after it is moved, and",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "142",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You need to purchase a third-party virtual security appliance that you will deploy to an Azure subscription.\nWhat should you use?\nA. Azure subscriptions\nB. Microsoft Defender for Cloud\nC. Azure Marketplace\nD. Microsoft Store",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "You can access these enhanced network security features by using an Azure partner solution. You can find the most current Azure partner network security solutions by visiting the Azure Marketplace, and searching for \"security\" and \"network security.\"",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "143",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "[…] is a highly secure IoT solution that includes a microcontroller unit (MCU) and a customized operatring system.\nA. Azure Arc\nB. Azure IoT Central\nC. Azure IoT Hub\nD. Azure Sphere",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Azure Arc is a hybrid cloud management solution that enables you to manage your servers, Kubernetes clusters, and applications across on-premises, multi-cloud, and edge environments from a single control plane.\nAzure IoT Central is an IoT application platform that simplifies the creation of IoT solutions. It enables you to connect, monitor, and manage your IoT devices at scale.\nAzure IoT Hub is a fully managed service that enables reliable and secure bidirectional communications between millions of IoT devices and an application back end.\nTherefore, the correct answer is Azure Sphere because it is the only option that includes a microcontroller unit (MCU) and a customized Linux operating system.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "144",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to deploy a service to Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the service will be available if a datacenter fails.\nWhat should you use as part of the virtual machine deployment?\nA. availability sets\nB. proximity placement groups\nC. host groups\nD. availability zones",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Azure availability zones are physically separate locations within each Azure region that are tolerant to local failures. Failures can range from software and hardware failures to events such as earthquakes, floods, and fires. Tolerance to failures is achieved because of redundancy and logical isolation of Azure services. To ensure resiliency, a minimum of three separate availability zones are present in all availability zone-enabled regions.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "145",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company has an Azure subscription that contains resources in several regions.\nYou need to ensure that administrators can only create resources in those regions.\nWhat should you use?\nA. a read-only lock\nB. an Azure policy\nC. a management group\nD. a reservation",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Explanation: Azure Policy evaluates resources and actions in Azure by comparing the properties of those resources to business rules. These business rules, described in JSON format, are known as policy definitions. To simplify management, several business rules can be grouped together to form a policy initiative (sometimes called a policySet). Once your business rules have been formed, the policy definition or initiative is assigned to any scope of resources that Azure supports, such as management groups, subscriptions, resource groups, or individual resources. The assignment applies to all resources within the Resource Manager scope of that assignment. Subscopes can be excluded, if necessary. For more information, see Scope in Azure Policy.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "146",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "An Azure region […].\nA. contains one or more data centers that are connected by using a low-latency network\nB. is found in each country where Microsoft has a subsidiary office\nC. can be found in every country in Europe and the Americas only\nD. contains one or more data center that are connected by using a high-latency network",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Box: contains one or more data centers that are connected by using a low-latency network.\nEach Azure region features datacenters deployed within a latency-defined perimeter. They're connected through a dedicated regional low-latency network. This design ensures that Azure services within any region offer the best possible performance and security.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "147",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You can use the Azure File Sync agent to sync on-premises data to an Azure […].\nA. blob container\nB. Data Lake Storage container\nC. file share\nD. queue",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "The Azure File Sync agent enables data on a Windows Server to be synchronized with an Azure File share.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "148",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "What is the function of a Site-to-Site VPN?\nA. provides a secure connection between a computer on a public network and the corporate network\nB. provides a dedicated private connection to Azure that does NOT travel over the internet\nC. provides a connection from an on-premises VPN device to an Azure VPN gateway",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "A Site-to-Site VPN gateway connection is used to connect your on-premises network to an Azure virtual network over an IPsec/IKE (IKEv1 or IKEv2) VPN tunnel.\nThis type of connection requires a VPN device located on-premises that has an externally facing public IP address assigned to it.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "149",
        "choices": "ABC123",
        "question": "A. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n1. Azure App Service\n2. Azure VM\n3. Microsoft Dynamic 365",
        "answer": "A2B1C3",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Platform as a service (PaaS)\nAzure App Service is a fully managed platform for building web applications.\nPlatform as a service (PaaS) is a complete development and deployment environment in the cloud, with resources that enable you to deliver everything from simple cloud-based apps to sophisticated, cloud-enabled enterprise applications.\nBox 2: Infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nWindows Azure Virtual Machines, an Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) offering in Windows Azure, was released back in 2012.\nBox 3: Software as a service (SaaS)\nDynamics 365 is a set of interconnected, modular Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) applications and services designed to both transform and enable your core customers, employees, and business activities.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "150",
        "choices": "ABC123",
        "question": "A. IaaS\nB. PaaS\nC. SaaS\n1. A cloud-based file server\n2. A cloud-based accounting system\n3. A cloud-based service for custom apps",
        "answer": "A1B3C2",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Infrastructure as a service (IaaS)\nAzure Files is a simple, secure, and serverless enterprise-grade cloud file shares.\nInfrastructure as a service (IaaS) is a type of cloud computing service that offers essential compute, storage, and networking resources on demand, on a pay-as- you-go basis.\nBox 2: Software as a service (SaaS)\nDynamics 365 is a set of interconnected, modular Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) applications and services designed to both transform and enable your core customers, employees, and business activities. It includes Dynamics 365 Finance: use the guided, rules-based chart of accounts and no-code configuration service to simplify regulatory reporting, electronic invoicing, and global payments.\nBox 3: Platform as a service (PaaS)\nPlatform as a service (PaaS) is a complete development and deployment environment in the cloud, with resources that enable you to deliver everything from simple cloud-based apps to sophisticated, cloud-enabled enterprise applications.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "151",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "Which two services can you use? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Azure Virtual Desktop\nB. Azure virtual machines\nC. Azure Functions\nD. Azure Container Instances\nE. Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)",
        "answer": "DE",
        "explanation": "Run Docker containers on-demand in a managed, serverless Azure environment. Azure Container Instances is a solution for any scenario that can operate in isolated containers, without orchestration. Run event-driven applications, quickly deploy from your container development pipelines, and run data processing and build jobs.\nYou can manage containers at scale with a fully managed Kubernetes container management and orchestration service that integrates with Azure Active\nDirectory.\nAzure Kubernetes Service is a robust and cost-effective container orchestration service that helps you to deploy and manage containerized applications in seconds where additional resources are assigned automatically without the headache of managing additional servers.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "152",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "When you need to delegate permissions to several Azure VM simultaneously, you must deploy the Azure VM […].\nA. to the same Azure region\nB. by using the same Azure Resource Manager template\nC. to the same resource group\nD. to the same availability zone\n",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "C. to the same resource group.\n\nThis is the correct answer because you can manage access control and permissions more efficiently by deploying Azure virtual machines to the same resource group. Azure allows you to apply RBAC (Role-Based Access Control) to resource groups, which means you can grant the same permissions to multiple virtual machines in the same resource group simultaneously. It simplifies the process of delegating permissions across multiple VMs.\n\nA. Deploying VMs to the same Azure region does not have any direct impact on the ability to delegate permissions. Regions define the physical location of data centers, not access control.\n\nB. Using the same Azure Resource Manager template is a method for deploying VMs with similar configurations but doesn't directly relate to managing permissions or access control.\n\nD. Deploying VMs to the same availability zone is a strategy for improving high availability and fault tolerance but doesn't inherently affect the delegation of permissions.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "153",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more availability zones.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Availability zones expand the level of control you have to maintain the availability of the applications and data on your VMs. An Availability Zone is a physically separate zone, within an Azure region. There are three Availability Zones per supported Azure region.\nEach Availability Zone has a distinct power source, network, and cooling. By architecting your solutions to use replicated VMs in zones, you can protect your apps and data from the loss of a datacenter. If one zone is compromised, then replicated apps and data are instantly available in another zone.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "154",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "This question requires that you evaluate the underlined text to determine if it is correct.\nOne of the benefits of Azure SQL Data Warehouse is that high availability is built into the platform.\nInstructions: Review the underlined text. If it makes the statement correct, select `No change is needed`. If the statement is incorrect, select the answer choice that makes the statement correct.\nA. No change is needed\nB. automatic scaling\nC. data compression\nD. versioning",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure Data Warehouse (now known as Azure Synapse Analytics) is a PaaS offering from Microsoft. As with all PaaS services from Microsoft, SQL Data\nWarehouse offers an availability SLA of 99.9%. Microsoft can offer 99.9% availability because it has high availability features built into the platform.\nReferences:",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "155",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYou plan to deploy several Azure virtual machines.\nYou need to ensure that the services running on the virtual machines are available if a single data center fails.\nSolution: You deploy the virtual machines to two or more regions.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "2 or more AZ\n2 or more Region",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "156",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "An Azure container instance is an example of an Azure […].\nA. compute service\nB. identify service\nC. networking service\nD. storage service",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "The term compute refers to the hosting model for the computing resources that your application runs on. For Azure this include:\nAzure Container Instances. The fastest and simplest way to run a container in Azure, without having to provision any virtual machines and without having to adopt a higher-level service.\nNote, and also the following:\nAzure App Service. A managed service for hosting web apps, mobile app back ends, RESTful APIs, or automated business processes.\nAzure Spring Cloud. A managed service designed and optimized for hosting Spring Boot apps.\nAzure Kubernetes Service (AKS). A managed Kubernetes service for running containerized applications.\nAzure Batch. A managed service for running large-scale parallel and high-performance computing (HPC) applications\nAzure Functions. A managed FaaS service.\nAzure Service Fabric. A distributed systems platform that can run in many environments, including Azure or on premises.\nAzure Virtual machines. Deploy and manage VMs inside an Azure virtual network.\nAzure Container Apps. Deploy and manage VMs inside an Azure virtual network.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "157",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "At which OSI layer does ExpressRoute operate?\nA. Layer 2\nB. Layer 3\nC. Layer 5\nD. Layer 7",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure ExpressRoute operates at Layer 3, the Network Layer, of the OSI model. \nThis layer is responsible for routing data packets across different networks, and ExpressRoute provides a dedicated, private connection between on-premises networks and Microsoft Azure data centers, bypassing the public internet. It facilitates enhanced network performance, reliability, and security for data transmission.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "158",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Application Insights is a feature of […].\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Application Gateway\nC. Azure Arc\nD. Azure Monitor",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Application Insights is a feature of Azure Monitor that provides extensible application performance management (APM) and monitoring for live web apps.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "159",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure resources can only access other resources in the same resource group. (Y/N)\n- If you delete a resource group, all the resources in the resource group will be deleted. (Y/N)\n- A resource group can contain resources from multiple Azure regions. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nA resource can interact with resources in other resource groups.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nDeleting the resource group will remove the resource group as well as all the resources in that resource group. This can be useful for the management of resources. For example, a virtual machine has several components (the VM itself, virtual disks, network adapter etc.). By placing the VM in its own resource group, you can delete the VM along with all its associated components by deleting the resource group.\nAnother example is when creating a test environment. You could place the entire test environment (Network components, virtual machines etc.) in one resource group. You can then delete the entire test environment by deleting the resource group.\n\nBox 3: Yes -\nResources from multiple different regions can be placed in a resource group. The resource group only contains metadata about the resources it contains.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "160",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "You plan to store 20 TB of data in Azure. The data will be accessed infrequently and visualized by using Microsoft Power BI.\nYou need to recommend a storage solution for the data.\nWhich two solutions should you recommend? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Azure Data Lake\nB. Azure Cosmos DB\nC. Azure SQL Data Warehouse\nD. Azure SQL Database\nE. Azure Database for PostgreSQL",
        "answer": "AC",
        "explanation": "You can use Power BI to analyze and visualize data stored in Azure Data Lake and Azure SQL Data Warehouse.\nAzure Data Lake includes all of the capabilities required to make it easy for developers, data scientists and analysts to store data of any size and shape and at any speed, and do all types of processing and analytics across platforms and languages. It removes the complexities of ingesting and storing all your data while making it faster to get up and running with batch, streaming and interactive analytics. It also integrates seamlessly with operational stores and data warehouses so that you can extend current data applications.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "161",
        "choices": "ABC123",
        "question": "You have an Azure environment that contains 10 web apps. To which URL should you connect to manage all the Azure resources?\nHttps://[…][…].com\nA. admin.\nB. portal.\nC. www.\n1. azure.\n2. azurewebsites.\n3. microsoft.",
        "answer": "B1",
        "explanation": "The Azure portal is a web-based management interface where you can view and manage all your Azure resources in one unified hub, including web apps, databases, virtual machines, virtual networks, storage and Visual Studio team projects.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "162",
        "choices": "ABC",
        "question": "Arrange the storage account redundancy options from the least redundant to the most redundant. To answer, move all options from the list of options to the answer area and arrange them in the correct order.\nA. Zone-redundant storage (ZRS)\nB. Geo-redundant storage (GRS)\nC. Locally-redundant storage (LRS)",
        "answer": "CAB",
        "explanation": "Think\nLRS = datacenter\nZRS = Zone\nGRS = Geographical Region",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "163",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Azure Blob Storage […].\nA. data store for queuing and reliably delivering messages between applications\nB. file share that can be mapped as a network drive\nC. key/attribute store for non-relational, structured data\nD. storage service optimized for very large objects, such as video files and bitmaps",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "BLOB = Binary Large Object",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "164",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "An Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs Linux and has the Azure CLI tools installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "A PowerShell script is a file that contains PowerShell cmdlets and code. A PowerShell script needs to be run in PowerShell.\nPowerShell can now be installed on Linux. However, the question states that the computer has Azure CLI tools, not PowerShell installed. Therefore, this solution does not meet the goal.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "165",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "An Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs Chrome OS and uses Azure Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "A PowerShell script is a file that contains PowerShell cmdlets and code. A PowerShell script needs to be run in PowerShell.\nWith the Azure Cloud Shell, you can run PowerShell cmdlets and scripts in a Web browser. You log in to the Azure Portal and select the Azure Cloud Shell option.\nThis will open a PowerShell session in the Web browser. The Azure Cloud Shell has the necessary Azure PowerShell module installed.\nNote: to run a PowerShell script in the Azure Cloud Shell, you need to change to the directory where the PowerShell script is stored.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "166",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- From Azure Service Health, an administrator can view the health of all the services in an Azure environment. (Y/N)\n- From Azure Service Health, an administrator can create a rule to be alerted if an Azure service fails. (Y/N)\n- From Azure Service Health, an administrator can prevent a service failure. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "YYN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Yes -\nAzure Service Health consists of three components: Azure Status, Azure Service Heath and Azure Resource Health.\nAzure service health provides a personalized view of the health of the Azure services and regions you're using. This is the best place to look for service impacting communications about outages, planned maintenance activities, and other health advisories because the authenticated Azure Service Health experience knows which services and resources you currently use.\nTo view the health of all other services available in Azure, you would use the Azure Status component of Azure Service Health. Azure status informs you of service outages in Azure on the Azure Status page. The page is a global view of the health of all Azure services across all Azure regions.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nThe best way to use Service Health is to set up Service Health alerts to notify you via your preferred communication channels when service issues, planned maintenance, or other changes may affect the Azure services and regions you use.\n\nBox 3: No -\nYou can use Resource Health to view the health of a virtual machine. However, you cannot use Resource Health to prevent a service failure affecting the virtual machine.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "167",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nAn Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs macOS and has PowerShell Core 6.0 installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Answer is B.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "168",
        "choices": "A",
        "question": "You need to view a list of planned maintenance events that can affect the availability of an Azure subscription.\nA. Dashboard>Help+Support> Service Health",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Answer is A.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "169",
        "choices": "ABCD1234",
        "question": "A. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Cognitive Services\nC. Azure Application Insights\nD. Azure DevOps\n1. An integrated solution for the deployment of code\n2. A tool that provides guidance and recommandations to improve an Azure environment\n3. A simplified tool to build intelligent Artificial Intelligence applications\n4. Monitors web applications",
        "answer": "A2B3C4D1",
        "explanation": "DevOps = code deploy\nAdvisor = guidance\nCognitive = Intelligence\nInsight = Monitor\n\nBox 1: Azure DevOps.\nAzure DevOps is Microsoft's primary software development and deployment platform.\nDevOps influences the application lifecycle throughout its plan, develop, deliver and operate phases.\nBox 2: Azure Advisor.\nAdvisor is a personalized cloud consultant that helps you follow best practices to optimize your Azure deployments. It analyzes your resource configuration and usage telemetry and then recommends solutions that can help you improve the cost effectiveness, performance, high availability, and security of your Azure resources.\nBox 3: Azure Cognitive Services.\nAzure Cognitive Services are APIs, SDKs, and services available to help developers build intelligent applications without having direct AI or data science skills or knowledge. Azure Cognitive Services enable developers to easily add cognitive features into their applications. The goal of Azure Cognitive Services is to help developers create applications that can see, hear, speak, understand, and even begin to reason. The catalog of services within Azure Cognitive Services can be categorized into five main pillars - Vision, Speech, Language, Web Search, and Decision.\nBox 4. Azure Application Insights.\nAzure Application Insights detects and diagnoses anomalies in web apps.\nApplication Insights, a feature of Azure Monitor, is an extensible Application Performance Management (APM) service for developers and DevOps professionals.\nUse it to monitor your live applications. It will automatically detect performance anomalies, and includes powerful analytics tools to help you diagnose issues and to understand what users actually do with your app.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "170",
        "choices": "ABCD1234",
        "question": "A. Azure HDInsight\nB. Azure Data Lake Analytics\nC. Azure SQL Synapse Analytics\nD. Azure SQL Database\n1. Azure HDInsight is an open-source framework for distributed processing and analysis of big data sets in clusters\n2. A cloud-based service that leverages massively parallel processing (MPP) to quickly run complex queries across petabytes of data in a relational database.\n3. Can run massively parallel data transformation and processing programs across petabytes of data.\n4. A managed relational cloud database service.",
        "answer": "A4B3C2D1",
        "explanation": "Relational: Sql\nMassive: Synapse\nMessive PetaByte: Lake\nOPenshource: Insight",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "171",
        "choices": "ABCD123",
        "question": "You need to identify which blades in the Azure portal must be used to perform the following tasks:\n- View security recommendations.\n- Monitor the health of Azure services.\n- Browse available virtual machine images.\nWhich blade should you identify for each task?\n\nA. Monitor\nB. Subscriptions\nC. Marketplace\nD. Advisor\n1. Monitor the health of Azure services.\n2. Browse available VM images.\n3. View security recommandations.",
        "answer": "A1C2D3",
        "explanation": "Box 1:\nAzure Monitor is used to monitor the health of Azure services.\nAzure Monitor maximizes the availability and performance of your applications and services by delivering a comprehensive solution for collecting, analyzing, and acting on telemetry from your cloud and on-premises environments. It helps you understand how your applications are performing and proactively identifies issues affecting them and the resources they depend on.\nBox 2:\nYou can browse available virtual machine images in the Azure Marketplace.\nAzure Marketplace provides access and information on solutions and services available from Microsoft and their partners. Customers can discover, try, or buy cloud software solutions built on or for Azure. The catalog of 8,000+ listings provides Azure building blocks, such as Virtual Machines (VMs), APIs, Azure apps,\nSolution Templates and managed applications, SaaS apps, containers, and consulting services.\nBox 3.\nAzure Advisor displays security recommendations.\nAzure Advisor provides you with a consistent, consolidated view of recommendations for all your Azure resources. It integrates with Azure Security Center to bring you security recommendations. You can get security recommendations from the Security tab on the Advisor dashboard.\nSecurity Center helps you prevent, detect, and respond to threats with increased visibility into and control over the security of your Azure resources. It periodically analyzes the security state of your Azure resources. When Security Center identifies potential security vulnerabilities, it creates recommendations. The recommendations guide you through the process of configuring the controls you need.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "172",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYou have an Azure environment. You need to create a new Azure virtual machine from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.\nSolution: You use Bash in Azure Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "With Azure Cloud Shell, you can create virtual machines using Bash or PowerShell.\nAzure Cloud Shell is an interactive, authenticated, browser-accessible shell for managing Azure resources. It provides the flexibility of choosing the shell experience that best suits the way you work, either Bash or PowerShell.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "173",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You have an on-premises application that sends email notifications automatically based on a rule.\nYou plan to migrate the application to Azure.\nYou need to recommend a serverless computing solution for the application.\nWhat should you include in the recommendation?\nA. a web app\nB. a server image in Azure Marketplace\nC. a logic app\nD. an API app",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Azure Logic Apps is a cloud service that helps you schedule, automate, and orchestrate tasks, business processes, and workflows when you need to integrate apps, data, systems, and services across enterprises or organizations. Logic Apps simplifies how you design and build scalable solutions for app integration, data integration, system integration, enterprise application integration (EAI), and business-to-business (B2B) communication, whether in the cloud, on premises, or both.\nFor example, here are just a few workloads you can automate with logic apps:\n- Process and route orders across on-premises systems and cloud services.\n- Send email notifications with Office 365 when events happen in various systems, apps, and services.\n- Move uploaded files from an SFTP or FTP server to Azure Storage.\n- Monitor tweets for a specific subject, analyze the sentiment, and create alerts or tasks for items that need review.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "174",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You plan to deploy a website to Azure. The website will be accessed by users worldwide and will host large video files.\nYou need to recommend which Azure feature must be used to provide the best video playback experience.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. an application gateway\nB. an Azure ExpressRoute circuit\nC. a content delivery network (CDN)\nD. an Azure Traffic Manager profile",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "The question states that users are located worldwide and will be downloading large video files. The video playback experience would be improved if they can download the video from servers in the same region as the users. We can achieve this by using a content deliver network.\nA content delivery network (CDN) is a distributed network of servers that can efficiently deliver web content to users. CDNs store cached content on edge servers in point-of-presence (POP) locations that are close to end users, to minimize latency.\nAzure Content Delivery Network (CDN) offers developers a global solution for rapidly delivering high-bandwidth content to users by caching their content at strategically placed physical nodes across the world. Azure CDN can also accelerate dynamic content, which cannot be cached, by leveraging various network optimizations using CDN POPs. For example, route optimization to bypass Border Gateway Protocol (BGP).\nThe benefits of using Azure CDN to deliver web site assets include:\n- Better performance and improved user experience for end users, especially when using applications in which multiple round-trips are required to load content.\n- Large scaling to better handle instantaneous high loads, such as the start of a product launch event.\n- Distribution of user requests and serving of content directly from edge servers so that less traffic is sent to the origin server.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "175",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "Your company plans to deploy several million sensors that will upload data to Azure.\nYou need to identify which Azure resources must be created to support the planned solution.\nWhich two Azure resources should you identify? Each correct answer presents part of the solution.\nA. Azure Data Lake\nB. Azure Queue storage\nC. Azure File Storage\nD. Azure IoT Hub\nE. Azure Notification Hubs",
        "answer": "AD",
        "explanation": "IoT Hub (Internet of things Hub) provides data from millions of sensors.\nIoT Hub is a managed service, hosted in the cloud, that acts as a central message hub for bi-directional communication between your IoT application and the devices it manages. You can use Azure IoT Hub to build IoT solutions with reliable and secure communications between millions of IoT devices and a cloud- hosted solution backend. You can connect virtually any device to IoT Hub.\nThere are two storage services IoT Hub can route messages to -- Azure Blob Storage and Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 (ADLS Gen2) accounts. Azure Data\nLake Storage accounts are hierarchical namespace-enabled storage accounts built on top of blob storage. Both of these use blobs for their storage.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "176",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "You have an Azure web app.\nYou need to manage the settings of the web app from an iPhone.\nWhat are two Azure management tools that you can use? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Azure CLI\nB. the Azure portal\nC. Azure Cloud Shell\nD. Windows PowerShell\nE. Azure Storage Explorer",
        "answer": "BC",
        "explanation": "The Azure portal is the web-based portal for managing Azure. Being web-based, you can use the Azure portal on an iPhone.\nAzure Cloud Shell is a web-based command line for managing Azure. You access the Azure Cloud Shell from the Azure portal. Being web-based, you can use the\nAzure Cloud Shell on an iPhone.\nIncorrect Answers:\nA: Azure CLI can be installed on MacOS but it cannot be installed on an iPhone.\nD: Windows PowerShell can be installed on MacOS but it cannot be installed on an iPhone.\nE: Azure Storage Explorer is not used to manage Azure web apps.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "177",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company plans to deploy an Artificial Intelligence (AI) solution in Azure.\nWhat should the company use to build, test, and deploy predictive analytics solutions?\nA. Azure Logic Apps\nB. Azure Machine Learning Designer\nC. Azure Batch\nD. Azure Cosmos DB",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure Machine Learning designer lets you visually connect datasets and modules on an interactive canvas to create machine learning models.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "178",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Advisor can generate a list of Azure virtual machines that are protected by Azure Backup. (Y/N)\n- If you implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor, your company's secure score will decrease. (Y/N)\n- To maintain Microsoft support, you must implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor within a period of 30 days. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NNN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure Advisor does not generate a list of virtual machines that ARE protected by Azure Backup. Azure Advisor does however, generate a list of virtual that ARE\nNOT protected by Azure Backup. You can view a list of virtual machines that are protected by Azure Backup by viewing the Protected Items in the Azure Recovery\nServices Vault.\n\nBox 2: No -\nIf you implement the security recommendations, you company's score will increase, not decrease.\n\nBox 3: No -\nThere is no requirement to implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor. The recommendations are just that, 'recommendations'. They are not 'requirements'.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "179",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What can you use to automatically send an alert if an administrator stops an Azure virtual machine?\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Service Health\nC. Azure Monitor\nD. Azure Network Watcher",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Azure Monitor is correct answer.\n\nAzure Service Health provides the health/status of Azure service.\n\nAzure Monitor - Provides Health/Status of your application using insights and logs",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "180",
        "choices": "ABCD1234",
        "question": "A. Azure Machine Learning\nB. Azure Synapse Analytics\nC. Azure IoT Hub\nD. Azure Functions\n1. Provides a cloud-based Enterprise Data Warehouse (EDW)\n2. Uses past training  to provide predictions that have high probability\n3. Provides serverless computing functionalities\n4. Processes data from millions of sensors",
        "answer": "A2B1C4D3",
        "explanation": "Box 1: Azure SQL Synapse Analytics\nAzure SQL Synapse Analytics (previously called Data Warehouse) is a cloud-based Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) offering from Microsoft. It is a large-scale, distributed, MPP (massively parallel processing) relational database technology in the same class of competitors as Amazon Redshift or Snowflake. Azure SQL\nSynapse Analytics is an important component of the Modern Data Warehouse multi-platform architecture. Because Azure SQL Synapse Analytics is an MPP system with a shared-nothing architecture across distributions, it is meant for large-scale analytical workloads which can take advantage of parallelism.\nBox 2:\nAzure Machine Learning uses past trainings to provide predictions that have high probability.\nMachine learning is a data science technique that allows computers to use existing data to forecast future behaviors, outcomes, and trends. By using machine learning, computers learn without being explicitly programmed.\nForecasts or predictions from machine learning can make apps and devices smarter. For example, when you shop online, machine learning helps recommend other products you might want based on what you've bought.\nBox 3:\nAzure Functions provides serverless computing functionalities.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.\nBox 4:\nIoT Hub (Internet of things Hub) provides data from millions of sensors.\nIoT Hub is a managed service, hosted in the cloud, that acts as a central message hub for bi-directional communication between your IoT application and the devices it manages. You can use Azure IoT Hub to build IoT solutions with reliable and secure communications between millions of IoT devices and a cloud- hosted solution backend. You can connect virtually any device to IoT Hub.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "181",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "You have an Azure environment.\nYou need to create a new Azure virtual machine from a tablet that runs the Android operating system.\nWhat are three possible solutions? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. Use Bash in Azure Cloud Shell.\nB. Use PowerShell in Azure Cloud Shell.\nC. Use the PowerApps portal.\nD. Use the Security & Compliance admin center.\nE. Use the Azure portal.",
        "answer": "ABE",
        "explanation": "The Android tablet device will have a web browser (Chrome). That's enough to connect to the Azure portal.\nThe Azure portal offers three ways to create a VM:\n- Using the graphical portal.\n- Using the Azure Cloud Shell using Bash.\n- Using the Azure Cloud Shell using PowerShell.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "182",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "A team of developers at your company plans to deploy, and then remove, 50 virtual machines each week. All the virtual machines are configured by using Azure\nResource Manager templates.\nYou need to recommend which Azure service will minimize the administrative effort required to deploy and remove the virtual machines.\nWhat should you recommend?\nA. Azure Reserved Virtual Machine (VM) Instances\nB. Azure DevTest Labs\nC. Azure virtual machine scale sets\nD. Azure Virtual Desktop",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "DevTest Labs creates labs consisting of pre-configured bases or Azure Resource Manager templates.\nBy using DevTest Labs, you can test the latest versions of your applications by doing the following tasks:\n- Quickly provision Windows and Linux environments by using reusable templates and artifacts.\n- Easily integrate your deployment pipeline with DevTest Labs to provision on-demand environments.\n- Scale up your load testing by provisioning multiple test agents and create pre-provisioned environments for training and demos.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "183",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- Azure Advisor can generate a list of Azure virtual machines that are protected by Azure Backup. (Y/N)\n- If you implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor, your company's secure score will decrease. (Y/N)\n- To maintain Microsoft support, you must implement the security recommendations provided by Azure Advisor within a period of 30 days. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYN",
        "explanation": "Box 1: No -\nAzure Advisor provides you with a consistent, consolidated view of recommendations for all your Azure resources. It integrates with Azure Security Center to bring you security recommendations. You can get security recommendations from the Security tab on the Advisor dashboard. Examples of recommendations include restricting access to virtual machines by configuring Network Security Groups, enabling storage encryption, installing vulnerability assessment solutions.\nHowever, Azure Advisor does not provide recommendations on how to improve the security of an Azure AD environment.\n\nBox 2: Yes -\nAdvisor helps you optimize and reduce your overall Azure spend by identifying idle and underutilized resources. You can get cost recommendations from the Cost tab on the Advisor dashboard.\nBox 3: No.\nAzure Advisor does not provide recommendations on how to configure network settings on Azure virtual machines.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "184",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS --generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From the Azure portal, launch Azure Cloud Shell and select PowerShell. Run the command in Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "The command can be run in the Azure Cloud Shell. Although this question says you select PowerShell rather than Bash, the Az commands will work in\nPowerShell.\nThe Azure Cloud Shell is a free interactive shell. It has common Azure tools preinstalled and configured to use with your account.\nTo open the Cloud Shell, just select Try it from the upper right corner of a code block. You can also launch Cloud Shell in a separate browser tab by going to",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "185",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS\n--generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From a computer that runs Windows 10, install Azure CLI. From PowerShell, sign in to Azure and then run the command.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "The command can be run from PowerShell or the command prompt if you have the Azure CLI installed.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "186",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "You have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS\n--generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From a computer that runs Windows 10, install Azure CLI. From a command prompt, sign in to Azure and then run the command.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "The command can be run from PowerShell or the command prompt if you have the Azure CLI installed.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "187",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Several support engineers plan to manage Azure by using the computers shown in the following table.\nYou need to identify which Azure management tools can be used from each computer.\nWhat should you identify for each computer? To answer, select the appropriate options in the answer area.\n- Computer1 : Windows 10\n- Computer2: Ubuntu\n- Computer3: MacOS Mojave\nA. The Azure CLI and the Azure portal\nB. The Azure portal and Azure Powershell\nC. The Azure CLI and Azure Powershell\nD. The Azure CLI, the Azure portal and Azure Powershell\n\n",
        "answer": "D",
        "explanation": "Previously, the Azure CLI (or x-plat CLI) was the only option for managing Azure subscriptions and resources from the command-line on Linux and macOS. Now with the open source and cross-platform release of PowerShell, you'll be able to manage all your Azure resources from Windows, Linux and macOS using your tool of choice, either the Azure CLI or Azure PowerShell cmdlets.\nThe Azure portal runs in a web browser so can be used in either operating system.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "188",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "You can access Compliance Manager from the […].\nA. Azure Active Directory admin center\nB. Azure portal\nC. Microsoft 365 admin center\nD. Microsoft Service Trust portal",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Go to the Microsoft Purview compliance portal and sign in with your Microsoft 365 global administrator account.\nSelect Compliance Manager on the left navigation pane. You'll arrive at your Compliance Manager dashboard.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "189",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "[…] a common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure and for implementing consistency across the Azure environment.\nA. Azure policy provide\nB. Resource groups provide\nC. Azure Resource Manager templates\nD. Management groups provide",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Azure Resource Manager templates provides a common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure and for implementing consistency across the\nAzure environment.\nAzure policies are used to define rules for what can be deployed and how it should be deployed. Whilst this can help in ensuring consistency, Azure policies do not provide the common platform for deploying objects to a cloud infrastructure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "190",
        "choices": "ABCD4",
        "question": "A. Azure Machine Learning\nB. Azure IoT Hub\nC. Azure Bot Services\nD. Azure Functions\n1.Provides a digital online assistant that provides speech support.\n2.Uses past trainings to provide predictions that have high probability.\n3.Provides serverless computing functionalities.\n4. Processes data from millions of sensors.",
        "answer": "A2B4C1D3",
        "explanation": "Box 1:\nAzure Bot Services provides a digital online assistant that provides speech support.\nBots provide an experience that feels less like using a computer and more like dealing with a person - or at least an intelligent robot. They can be used to shift simple, repetitive tasks, such as taking a dinner reservation or gathering profile information, on to automated systems that may no longer require direct human intervention. Users converse with a bot using text, interactive cards, and speech. A bot interaction can be a quick question and answer, or it can be a sophisticated conversation that intelligently provides access to services.\nBox 2:\nAzure Machine Learning uses past trainings to provide predictions that have high probability.\nMachine learning is a data science technique that allows computers to use existing data to forecast future behaviors, outcomes, and trends. By using machine learning, computers learn without being explicitly programmed.\nForecasts or predictions from machine learning can make apps and devices smarter. For example, when you shop online, machine learning helps recommend other products you might want based on what you've bought.\nBox 3:\nAzure Functions provides serverless computing functionalities.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.\nBox 4:\nIoT Hub (Internet of things Hub) provides data from millions of sensors.\nIoT Hub is a managed service, hosted in the cloud, that acts as a central message hub for bi-directional communication between your IoT application and the devices it manages. You can use Azure IoT Hub to build IoT solutions with reliable and secure communications between millions of IoT devices and a cloud- hosted solution backend. You can connect virtually any device to IoT Hub.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "191",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nAn Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nSolution: Run the script from a computer that runs Windows 10 and has the Azure PowerShell module installed.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "A PowerShell script is a file that contains PowerShell cmdlets and code. A PowerShell script needs to be run in PowerShell.\nIn this question, the computer has the Azure PowerShell module installed. Therefore, this solution does meet the goal.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "192",
        "choices": "ABCD1234",
        "question": "A. Azure Functions\nB. Azure App Service\nC. Azure Virtual Machines\nD. Azure Container Instances\n1. Provide operating system virtualization\n2. Provide portable environment for virtualized applications\n3. Used to build, deploy, and scale web apps\n4. Provide a platform for serverless code",
        "answer": "A4B3C1D2",
        "explanation": "Box 1:\nAzure virtual machines provide operation system virtualization.\nAzure Virtual Machines (VM) is one of several types of on-demand, scalable computing resources that Azure offers. Typically, you choose a VM when you need more control over the computing environment than the other choices offer.\nBox 2:\nAzure Container Instances provide portable environments for virtualized applications.\nContainers are becoming the preferred way to package, deploy, and manage cloud applications. Azure Container Instances offers the fastest and simplest way to run a container in Azure, without having to manage any virtual machines and without having to adopt a higher-level service.\nContainers offer significant startup benefits over virtual machines (VMs). Azure Container Instances can start containers in Azure in seconds, without the need to provision and manage VMs.\nBox 3:\nAzure App Service is used to build, deploy and scale web apps.\nAzure App Service is a platform-as-a-service (PaaS) offering that lets you create web and mobile apps for any platform or device and connect to data anywhere, in the cloud or on-premises. App Service includes the web and mobile capabilities that were previously delivered separately as Azure Websites and Azure Mobile\nServices.\nBox 4:\nAzure Functions provide a platform for serverless code.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "draganddrop"
    },
    {
        "id": "193",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Which service provides serverless computing in Azure?\nA. Azure Virtual Machines\nB. Azure Functions\nC. Azure storage account\nD. Azure dedicated hosts",
        "answer": "B",
        "explanation": "Azure Functions provide a platform for serverless code.\nAzure Functions is a serverless compute service that lets you run event-triggered code without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "194",
        "choices": "ABCDE",
        "question": "An Azure administrator plans to run a PowerShell script that creates Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend which computer configuration to use to run the script.\nWhich three computers can run the script? Each correct answer presents a complete solution.\nNOTE: Each correct selection is worth one point.\nA. a computer that runs macOS and has PowerShell Core 6.0 installed.\nB. a computer that runs Windows 10 and has the Azure PowerShell module installed.\nC. a computer that runs Linux and has the Azure PowerShell module installed.\nD. a computer that runs Linux and has the Azure CLI tools installed.\nE. a computer that runs Chrome OS and uses Azure Cloud Shell.",
        "answer": "BCE",
        "explanation": "A: wrong, you need Azure Powershell Module, Powershell only isn't enoght\nB: correct, you have Powershell and the module to create Azure resources\nC: correct, you have Powershell and the module to create Azure resources\nD: wrong, with Azure CLI you don't execute Powershell script\nE: correct, from a browser you can connect to Azure Portal and execute Azure Powershell comdlet",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "195",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "After you answer a question in this section, you will NOT be able to return to it. As a result, these questions will not appear in the review screen.\nYou have an Azure subscription named Subscription1. You sign in to the Azure portal and create a resource group named RG1.\nFrom Azure documentation, you have the following command that creates a virtual machine named VM1. az vm create --resource-group RG1 --name VM1 --image UbuntuLTS --generate-ssh-keys\nYou need to create VM1 in Subscription1 by using the command.\nSolution: From the Azure portal, launch Azure Cloud Shell and select Bash. Run the command in Cloud Shell.\nDoes this meet the goal?\nA. Yes\nB. No",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "The answer is correct, the given command is a bash one, and Azure CLI accessed from the Azure cloud shell is the right approach to writing and running it.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "yesno"
    },
    {
        "id": "196",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "Your company has several business units.\nEach business unit requires 20 different Azure resources for daily operation. All the business units require the same type of Azure resources.\nYou need to recommend a solution to automate the creation of the Azure resources.\nWhat should you include in the recommendations?\nA. Azure Resource Manager templates\nB. virtual machine scale sets\nC. the Azure API Management service\nD. management groups",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "You can use Azure Resource Manager templates to automate the creation of the Azure resources. Deploying resource through templates is known as\n'Infrastructure as code'.\nTo implement infrastructure as code for your Azure solutions, use Azure Resource Manager templates. The template is a JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) file that defines the infrastructure and configuration for your project. The template uses declarative syntax, which lets you state what you intend to deploy without having to write the sequence of programming commands to create it. In the template, you specify the resources to deploy and the properties for those resources.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "197",
        "choices": "YN",
        "question": "For each of the following statements, select Yes if the statement is true. \nOtherwise, select No.\n- You can use Azure Cost Management to view costs associated to management groups. (Y/N)\n- You can use Azure Cost Management to view costs associated to resource groups. (Y/N)\n- You can use Azure Cost Management to view the usage of virtual machines during the last three months. (Y/N)",
        "answer": "NYY",
        "explanation": "Management groups also allow grouping subscriptions together, but offer a few key differences:\nManagement group access is inherited down to the subscriptions and resources.\nManagement groups can be layered into multiple levels and subscriptions can be placed at any level.\nManagement groups aren't included in cost details.\nAll historical costs are returned for management groups based on the subscriptions currently within that hierarchy. When a subscription moves, all historical cost moves.\nManagement groups are supported by Azure Policy and can have rules assigned to automate compliance reporting for your cost governance strategy.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "hotspot"
    },
    {
        "id": "198",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "What can you use to identify underutilized or unused Azure virtual machines?\nA. Azure Advisor\nB. Azure Cost Management + Billing\nC. Azure reservations\nD. Azure Policy",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure Advisor helps you optimize and reduce your overall Azure spend by identifying idle and underutilized resources. You can get cost recommendations from the Cost tab on the Advisor dashboard.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "199",
        "choices": "ABCDEFGHIJK",
        "question": "Which node in the Azure portal should you use to assign a user the Reader role for a resource group? To answer, select the node in the answer area.\nA. Overview\nB. Activity log\nC. Access control (IAM)\nD. Tags\nE. Resource visualizer\nF. Events\nG. Resource costs\nH. Deployments\nI. Security\nJ. Policies\nK. Properties",
        "answer": "C",
        "explanation": "Identity Acces amnagement is the answer (IAM)",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    },
    {
        "id": "200",
        "choices": "ABCD",
        "question": "[…] is an Apache Spark-based analytics service.\nA. Azure Databricks\nB. Azure Data Factory\nC. Azure DevOps\nD. Azure Synapse Analytics",
        "answer": "A",
        "explanation": "Azure Databricks is a fast, easy, and collaborative Apache Spark-based big data analytics service designed for data science and data engineering.",
        "counter": 0,
        "certifcode": "az-900",
        "questiontype": "multiplechoice"
    }
]